<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/</link><description>Recent content on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:52:28 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top Albums of 2020</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/10/top-albums-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 18:52:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/10/top-albums-of-2020/</guid><description>This year was full of unexpected surprises, disappointments, and more for everyone, but music was here to comfort us throughout. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of favorite albums for the year:
Hum - Inlet Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s talked music with me long enough has heard me express my adoration for Hum. They were the first/one of the first bands I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live. Their particular brand of space rock/shoegaze/whatever-you-want-to-call-it has always been one of my favorites.</description></item><item><title>Jetpack Benchmark on Firebase Test Lab</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/03/06/jetpack-benchmark-on-firebase-test-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 10:30:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/03/06/jetpack-benchmark-on-firebase-test-lab/</guid><description>As previously outlined in my talk at Mobius Conference in Saint Petersburg last year, our team at Zalando is building a server-driven UI platform we call AppCraft. AppCraft allows us to add or update screens in our app with only server changes instead of the normal app release constrained way of doing things.
On the client side, we are building every screen the same way: fetch layout &amp;amp; data from the server, parse it, and render it.</description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2019</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/23/top-albums-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 17:47:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/23/top-albums-of-2019/</guid><description>Time files and it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s been several years since I last shared my favorite albums of the year. Despite the lack of posts, I still keep a list every year and decided it&amp;rsquo;s time once again to highlight some of the albums I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed most:
Oh Sees - Face Stabber Any year that includes an Oh Sees release will find it in my top albums list, so here it is.</description></item><item><title>AppCraft: Faster Than a Speeding Release Train</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/22/appcraft-faster-than-a-speeding-release-train/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 16:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/22/appcraft-faster-than-a-speeding-release-train/</guid><description>It was a pleasure speaking at Mobius Conference in Saint Petersburg this past May. I never got around to finishing the transcript of the talk I intended to write, but you can find the slides on Speaker Deck and the video on YouTube:</description></item><item><title>Introducing Biografy</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/12/24/introducing-biografy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 20:53:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/12/24/introducing-biografy/</guid><description>What is Biografy? Biografy is a lifelogging app that automatically builds a timeline of each day. The Events view logs events from various apps including music, podcasts, videos, calls and chats. Each event includes rich detail such as the time, activity (stationary, walking, biking, etc.), and location/place. The Motion view lists car/transit trips, bike rides, runs, and walks. With the Map view, you can see where you were when each event occurred and gain insights like where you spend your time based on the clusters of pins.</description></item><item><title>React Native: Is It Worth It?</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/11/27/react-native-is-it-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 21:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/11/27/react-native-is-it-worth-it/</guid><description>Intro When new technologies start gaining momentum in the Android community, the pragmatic (or lazy) among us eventually have to ask ourselves, “Is it worth it?” After the initial arrival and departure of the hype train, some of these become trusted tools we use in almost every app. Think RxJava and Dagger.
React Native may be on its way to earning a place in the same club. Once we get past the fact that JavaScript on Android and HTML in JavaScript seem pretty damn weird at first, there’s a lot to like.</description></item><item><title>Things I've Learned Since Moving to Berlin</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 12:45:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Berlin for a bit more than six months now. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned:
It is possible to survive a summer without air conditioning. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to go all summer without a mosquito bite. I don&amp;rsquo;t miss having a car. Public transit is great here so I typically only need one to haul things like furniture. And I can rent one on demand pretty easily with apps like DriveNow.</description></item><item><title>Aufwiedersehen, Houston! Hallo, Berlin!</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 13:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</guid><description>Anyone who has talked to me for more than 10 minutes has probably heard me mention my love for Berlin. I first visited the city about six years ago and almost immediately resolved to make it my home one day. I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to finally announce that it&amp;rsquo;s happening! I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining Zalando in Berlin next month to do Android and hopefully step up my fashion game a bit. Radical Agility sounds like engineering nirvana to me!</description></item><item><title>Multiple Developers, One App: How to Not Break Everything</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/10/22/multiple-developers-one-app-how-to-not-break-everything/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 13:00:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/10/22/multiple-developers-one-app-how-to-not-break-everything/</guid><description>This was my third time attending the Big Android BBQ in Hurst, TX and my third time to present at it. Perhaps my favorite thing about the conference (aside from the obvious BBQ) is reconnecting with old friends and making new ones. This year I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of meeting people from all over the world and learning that we know a lot of the same people. Small world, indeed.</description></item><item><title>Things That Suck About Android Development</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/03/18/things-that-suck-about-android-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 13:17:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/03/18/things-that-suck-about-android-development/</guid><description>I presented &amp;ldquo;Things That Suck About Android Development&amp;rdquo; at this year&amp;rsquo;s mdevcon conference in Amsterdam. It&amp;rsquo;s a great conference in an amazing city. I highly recommend it to anyone developing mobile apps.
The title is admittedly a bit sensational, but my goal was to highlight many of the painful parts about developing for Android and how to avoid/fix them.
Here are the slides!</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2015</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late with my annual Top 10 list, but here it is roughly ranked by Google Music play count:
Earl Sweatshirt - I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Shit, I Don&amp;rsquo;t Go Outside I was finally lucky enough to see him live and he didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint. Another great release. This soundtracked numerous skateboard and chill sessions. Vince Staples - Summertime &amp;lsquo;06 His &amp;ldquo;Hell Can Wait&amp;rdquo; EP made my list last year and I knew this one would be on this year&amp;rsquo;s list right away.</description></item><item><title>Using a Third Party FAB with CoordinatorLayout</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/28/using-a-third-party-fab-with-coordinatorlayout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/28/using-a-third-party-fab-with-coordinatorlayout/</guid><description>Before the Design Support Library was announced at Google I/O last month, I had numerous third party libraries in my projects for various elements of Material Design. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed replacing the nav drawer, tabs, and parallax scrolling libraries with their support library counterparts. However, on one of my projects, we needed an expanding floating action button (FAB) similar to the one in Inbox, which the support library does not currently provide.</description></item><item><title>The Time I Interviewed at Google</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/09/the-time-i-interviewed-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/09/the-time-i-interviewed-at-google/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a pretty big secret for the past month or so; something that only my friends and family know about. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, sneaking around interviewing for a new job like we&amp;rsquo;re having an affair. Only this time, it was different. As an Android developer, this was like trying out for the majors. No&amp;hellip;seriously, y&amp;rsquo;all&amp;hellip;Google invited me to interview.
My adventure started early last month as I was triaging my inbox.</description></item><item><title>Loading a List of Objects from Firebase</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/04/06/loading-a-list-of-objects-from-firebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/04/06/loading-a-list-of-objects-from-firebase/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Firebase lately in preparation for adding data synchronization to my Music Library app. Their docs did a great job of getting me set up. Using the sample app as a guide, I even got Google+ OAuth working without much trouble. From there, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to load data into a Firebase instance partitioned by Google account. All that was left was to query the data out of Firebase and I&amp;rsquo;d be able to see the sync magic in action.</description></item><item><title>Why I'm Unironically Carrying This Small, Older Android Phone</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</guid><description>I thoroughly enjoyed my last night in Berlin a little over a week ago; so much that I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice my phone was missing until the end of the night. Shake your head and say it couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen to you. I thought the same thing until it did. Normally, I keep my phone in one of my front pockets, but I was wearing a coat that covered the pocket, making it a bit more difficult to grab my phone quickly to check Google Maps.</description></item><item><title>MCE Conference 2015 - Automated Testing for Modern Android Applications</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/08/mce-conference-2015-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/08/mce-conference-2015-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</guid><description>It was an honor to speak at and attend MCE Conference in Warsaw last week. I participated in a workshop where I learned about prototyping with Android and Arduinos. I attended talks about Groovy, Kotlin, Proguard, design, scaling apps for emerging markets, and some handy new libraries.
That alone easily makes MCE one of the best conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. On top of all that, the networking with fellow speakers and attendees was a personal highlight.</description></item><item><title>Running Shell Commands with Gradle and a Better Way to Delombok</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/01/22/running-shell-commands-with-gradle-and-a-better-way-to-delombok/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/01/22/running-shell-commands-with-gradle-and-a-better-way-to-delombok/</guid><description>A few months ago, I posted about how to use Gradle tasks to &amp;ldquo;delombok&amp;rdquo; code using Lombok annotations before generating Javadocs. My solution for running the delombok task used Ant and was based on what I found after the requisite Google &amp;amp; StackOverflow searching. This worked just fine until Android Studio 1.0 and the associated Gradle build tools were released at the end of the year.
The crux of the problem appeared to be a change in the way dependencies are merged during compilation.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2014</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</guid><description>The end of another year means it&amp;rsquo;s time for the annual Top 10 Favorite Albums list.
Ty Segall - Manipulator While not the leader in sheer track plays via my Google Play Music account, this album is perfect all the way through. It certainly spent a lot of time on my turntable as well. Nothing - Guilty of Everything A wonderful example of the specific brand of rock music I love.</description></item><item><title>Music Library 3.0 - Material Design Update</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/11/02/music-library-3.0-material-design-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/11/02/music-library-3.0-material-design-update/</guid><description>I started developing Music Library about four years ago when I wanted an app for organizing my record collection. Armed with my Nexus One, Eclipse, and a copy of Apress&amp;rsquo; Pro Android, I spent my nights and weekends learning the inner workings of my now-favorite mobile OS.
Over the years, Music Library has been a playground of sorts for exploring various open source libraries, patterns, and best practices. While there is still a fair amount of code I would write differently today (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, ContentProvider), the app has been and continues to be an enjoyable side project.</description></item><item><title>BABBQ5 - Automated Testing for Modern Android Applications</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/17/babbq5-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/17/babbq5-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</guid><description>This is my third year to attend and present at the Big Android BBQ. My talk this year showed how to prepare an Android app for automated testing using mocking, dependency injection, and Google&amp;rsquo;s super fast Espresso test runner. You can find the presentation on Speaker Deck and the sample code on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Hosting Android Dependencies on GitHub</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/05/hosting-android-dependencies-on-github/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/05/hosting-android-dependencies-on-github/</guid><description>As I mentioned in my last post, I&amp;rsquo;m developing an SDK at work. The libraries I use most frequently in my apps are all included as Maven dependencies. Adding a line to my build.gradle file is much preferred to downloading a JAR file. To make the SDK as easy as possible for developers to include in their projects, I wanted to deliver it the same way.
Maven Central is the de facto repository for open source library hosting.</description></item><item><title>Delombok and Javadoc with Gradle</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/09/29/delombok-and-javadoc-with-gradle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/09/29/delombok-and-javadoc-with-gradle/</guid><description>I recently had my first experience working with Javadoc to generate documentation for an SDK I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing at work. In general, I&amp;rsquo;m in the &amp;ldquo;clean code doesn&amp;rsquo;t need comments&amp;rdquo; camp, but SDKs tend to be a limited view into a larger abstraction, so good documentation is a necessity.
Javadoc has been around since the introduction of the Java language, so I won&amp;rsquo;t include a primer here. If you want to learn more, Oracle has you covered.</description></item><item><title>Android's Material Design and The Bauhaus</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/13/androids-material-design-and-the-bauhaus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/13/androids-material-design-and-the-bauhaus/</guid><description>Since Android Gingerbread (v2.3), loyalists know that each version has an Easter egg that can be accessed by repeatedly tapping the version number on the Settings &amp;gt; About screen. The Android &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo; Preview is no exception.
While test driving the new version, I naturally had to see what Google had hidden for me in their latest release. Previous versions have had everything from gingerbread zombies to Nyandroids and a pile of jelly beans.</description></item><item><title>Fun with Android Wear</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/12/fun-with-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/12/fun-with-android-wear/</guid><description>I got my LG G Android Wear smart watch earlier this week and dove right into developing for it.
My first project was Deutsch Uhr, a text-based German language watch face inspired by my favorite Pebble watch face. I had fun adding animations for the hour/minute/day changes and learning what makes a Wear app tick (pun intended, I always do). A big thanks to my friend Daniel Ward for help getting started.</description></item><item><title>Google I/O 2014: An Android Developer's Perspective</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/06/28/google-i/o-2014-an-android-developers-perspective/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/06/28/google-i/o-2014-an-android-developers-perspective/</guid><description>This year’s Google I/O developer conference once again gave developers plenty to be excited about. As expected, we heard about the next release of the Android operating system, Android Wear smart watches, and updated development tools. Rumored products &amp;amp; services such as Android TV, Android Auto, and Google Fit were also announced. Perhaps the most exciting and far-reaching announcement was the new Material Design language, which replaces the now dated looking Holo with a consistent look for all platforms.</description></item><item><title>Droidcon Berlin 2014: Froyo to KitKat</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/05/09/droidcon-berlin-2014-froyo-to-kitkat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/05/09/droidcon-berlin-2014-froyo-to-kitkat/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to be speaking at Droidcon Berlin this year. I fell in love with the city on my first visit and the conference was a perfect reason for another visit. Attempts to try out my very basic German skills have shown me that I have a long way to go. However, I am proud to say that I have managed to make a few purchases without panicking and falling back to English.</description></item><item><title>Developing for Android Tutorial</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/04/04/developing-for-android-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/04/04/developing-for-android-tutorial/</guid><description>I gave a two hour tutorial on developing for Android at work today for our weekly tech talk. Similar in style to my coworker Aaron Ortbals&amp;rsquo; tutorial on Ember.js, I showed how to build a client for GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Events API.
Topics included:
Project setup Gradle dependencies API requests &amp;amp; JSON parsing Activities &amp;amp; fragments Lists, adapters, and custom item layouts You can find the source code and the slides for the tutorial on GitHub.</description></item><item><title>Presenting: Wrist Presenter for Android and the Pebble Smartwatch</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/03/07/presenting-wrist-presenter-for-android-and-the-pebble-smartwatch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/03/07/presenting-wrist-presenter-for-android-and-the-pebble-smartwatch/</guid><description>Shortly after getting a Pebble Smartwatch this past Christmas, my coworker and all-around-cool-dude Matthew Morey asked me if I&amp;rsquo;d be interested in developing the Android version of his Wrist Presenter iOS app. Luckily, he already had a rock solid Pebble app developed, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to flex my meager C programming skills.
Wrist Presenter turns your Pebble Smartwatch into a remote for presentations running on your Android or iOS device.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Kollektor</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</guid><description>Why a new app? When I first decided to get into Android development, I created the Music Library app to catalog my vinyl collection. It served me well as I learned the ins and outs of Android programming including content providers, interacting with other applications via intents, working with the file system to save/load images, making API requests, etc. In order to test the workings of the Android app market, I published the ad supported Music Library Free and the paid Music Library versions of the app.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2013</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</guid><description>Each year, I keep a list of albums that I find myself listening to frequently. This is the time of year when I review the list and pick my top 10. I ventured into hip-hop and electronic music a bit more this year. Psych rock and 90s style fuzz are also well represented.
My Bloody Valentine - MBV Disclosure - Settle Swearin&amp;rsquo; - Dust in the Gold Sack Weed - Deserve Thee Oh Sees - Floating Coffin Night Beats - Sonic Bloom Speedy Ortiz - Major Arcana Unknown Mortal Orchestra - II Waxahatchee - Cerulean Salt Earl Sweatshirt - Doris</description></item><item><title>Signing Volley Requests with Scribe</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/15/signing-volley-requests-with-scribe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/15/signing-volley-requests-with-scribe/</guid><description>When I initially needed to integrate OAuth request signing with Volley in my Android app, I used the Signpost library. It was fairly straightforward to build a URL, pass it to the Signpost OAuthConsumer, and retrieve a new string with the appropriate OAuth parameters added. Unfortunately, as you can see from the commit history, there has been very little activity over the past year.
Increasingly, I see recommendations for Scribe. The project is very active and it makes implementing OAuth request signing as easy as it&amp;rsquo;s likely to get.</description></item><item><title>TechStreet Houston: Intro to Android Programming</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/11/20/techstreet-houston-intro-to-android-programming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/11/20/techstreet-houston-intro-to-android-programming/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m giving another Intro to Android Programming talk at TechStreet Houston today. The slides are very similar to my previous talk at Houston TechFest, but here is the link for today&amp;rsquo;s presentation.</description></item><item><title>Things I Learned at Big Android BBQ 2013</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/13/things-i-learned-at-big-android-bbq-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/13/things-i-learned-at-big-android-bbq-2013/</guid><description>T-Mobile reception is still terrible at the conference center. Alcohol purchases spike in the City of Hurst as a result of the conference. The guys from Willow Tree Apps have released some awesome Android open source libraries (BetterPickers, OAK, and RPatch) It&amp;rsquo;s worth the short drive to Roots Coffee each morning. High Roller makes adult size big wheels. They are a ton of fun to ride. Oppo makes some pretty sweet phones.</description></item><item><title>Big Android BBQ 2013 - Android Open Source Libraries You Need in Your Life</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/11/big-android-bbq-2013-android-open-source-libraries-you-need-in-your-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/11/big-android-bbq-2013-android-open-source-libraries-you-need-in-your-life/</guid><description>This is my second year to speak at the Big Android BBQ in Hurst, TX. My talk covered a slew of handy open source libraries to accelerate the development of modern Android applications.
The slides are available on Google Drive.
I&amp;rsquo;m having a blast at the conference. The sessions so far have been great. I hope to see all of you here again next year!</description></item><item><title>Houston TechFest: Intro to Android Programming</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/09/28/houston-techfest-intro-to-android-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/09/28/houston-techfest-intro-to-android-programming/</guid><description>I gave an Intro to Android Programming presentation today at Houston TechFest. The slides are available on Google Drive.
Thanks to everyone who attended. Keep Android trill!</description></item><item><title>Migrating from Ant to Gradle</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/08/06/migrating-from-ant-to-gradle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/08/06/migrating-from-ant-to-gradle/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk on migrating a custom Eclipse/Ant build to Android Studio/Gradle at tonight&amp;rsquo;s Houston Android Developers meetup. The slides are available on Google Drive.
I hope to see you there!</description></item><item><title>Surprised this domain was available</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/07/14/surprised-this-domain-was-available/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/07/14/surprised-this-domain-was-available/</guid><description>I finally got around to registering a domain name and setting up a basic Octopress site. I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting here about music/code/coffee/beer/life releated stuff when the mood strikes.</description></item><item><title>Setting item selected state in Android GridView</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/09/25/setting-item-selected-state-in-android-gridview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/09/25/setting-item-selected-state-in-android-gridview/</guid><description>When working with the GridView in an Android app recently, I ran into a very strange behavior around setting the selected state for a view created in my ArrayAdapter's getView() method. I'm using selectors to handle the drawable states and everything works properly when tapping a list item to select/tapping again to unselect. When debugging the ArrayAdapter's getView() method, I could see that the selected state was being set to the correct value when calling view.</description></item><item><title>A Functional Queue in JavaScript</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/02/03/a-functional-queue-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/02/03/a-functional-queue-in-javascript/</guid><description>It's been over a year since I've posted here, but I've been busy delving into Android and Ruby on Rails among other things. To get back into blogging (hopefully more regularly...we'll see), I thought I'd share an interesting JavaScript exercise I was asked to complete as part of a job interview recently. The task was to build a functional queue in JavaScript. A functional queue is a queue (first in, first out) which is implemented with no side-effects.</description></item><item><title>My Top 10 Albums of 2010</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/12/28/my-top-10-albums-of-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/12/28/my-top-10-albums-of-2010/</guid><description>Since I put together my inaugural Top 10 list last year, I may as well make it a tradition. Luckily I had the foresight to keep a running list in Evernote throughout the year, so the tough part was putting them in order. Some may argue about the order of the albums on the list or the exclusion of others. I'd love to hear your opinions.
So without any further jibba jabba, here's my Top 10 Albums of 2010 list: Local Natives - Gorilla Manor The harmonies are amazing.</description></item><item><title>Things To Do While I'm on Vacation in December</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/11/22/things-to-do-while-im-on-vacation-in-december/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/11/22/things-to-do-while-im-on-vacation-in-december/</guid><description>I didn't take much of my vacation time this year, so I'm left with thirteen days of vacation to take in December. In an effort to make the most of this bounty of time off, I made a list of things to do. Thanks to Jamie for suggesting I make a list after patiently enduring my first couple brainstorming sessions.
Here's the list in no particular order:
Triumphant return to homebrewing - Brew an American Pale Ale.</description></item><item><title>Indie Rock Mix CD for My Canada/Montreal Trip</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/07/07/indie-rock-mix-cd-for-my-canada/montreal-trip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/07/07/indie-rock-mix-cd-for-my-canada/montreal-trip/</guid><description>Any good trip needs a soundtrack. With this in mind, I created a mix CD with the following tracks. All of the bands except where noted hail from Montreal or at least Canada. I've included links to listen to the tracks on YouTube. No Celine Dion or Bryan Adams will be found here, only the coolest indie bands Canada has to offer.
These are in no particular order. I know, I know.</description></item><item><title>My review of The Flaming Lips' "New Year's Eve Freakout"</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/01/02/my-review-of-the-flaming-lips-new-years-eve-freakout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/01/02/my-review-of-the-flaming-lips-new-years-eve-freakout/</guid><description>Since my friend Greg asked for it, here's a review of The Flaming Lips' "New Year's Eve Freakout" as their latest album, "Embryonic", spins on the turntable.
The last time I saw the Lips was in high school just after the release of "Clouds Taste Metallic". That experience and word-of-mouth since prepared me for the celebratory chaos that is a Flaming Lips show. Joe Mathlete of 29-95.com did a very entertaining set of cartoons documenting his trip to OKC for the show accurately described a Flaming Lips concert as "</description></item><item><title>Bands I've Seen Live</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 09:12:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking for quite some time about trying to compile a list of all the bands I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ll put these in order as much as possible. I plan to keep adding to this as I recall past shows and attend more in the future. I have a ticket stub book, so I&amp;rsquo;ll include the dates and other details for those I have. Some of these are special in that the bands have since split up, are no longer touring, and/or some members have passed away.</description></item><item><title>Happiness is a byproduct</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/01/05/happiness-is-a-byproduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/01/05/happiness-is-a-byproduct/</guid><description>The "Quote of the Day" on my Google homepage must repeat every year, because I'm sure I've seen this one before. Nevertheless, it's so true: Happiness is always a by-product. It is probably a matter of temperament, and for anything I know it may be glandular. But it is not something that can be demanded from life, and if you are not happy you had better stop worrying about it and see what treasures you can pluck from your own brand of unhappiness.</description></item><item><title>My latest adventures</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/11/08/my-latest-adventures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/11/08/my-latest-adventures/</guid><description>Again, too long between blog posts. My faithful readers are clammoring for more of my adventures. Right? Well, most likely not, but here it goes...
First, Jamie and I went to the ACL Festival in Austin about a month ago. It was the first time to go for both of us and we saw a ton of great bands including Vampire Weekend, Bobby Bare Jr, Mates of State, Jenny Lewis, Old 97's, Jose Gonzalez, Drive-By Truckers, Cansei de ser Sexy (CSS), MGMT, Conor Oberst, and Beck.</description></item><item><title>Ohhhhhhklahoma! Where the wind comes sweepin' down the plain...</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/09/18/ohhhhhhklahoma-where-the-wind-comes-sweepin-down-the-plain.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/09/18/ohhhhhhklahoma-where-the-wind-comes-sweepin-down-the-plain.../</guid><description>I hightailed it out of Houston last Wednesday when it was pretty clear Ike was gonna slap us around. Unlike most of those trying to evacuate, I eschewed the ever popular I-10 and I-45 routes for Highway 6. I followed that up through Waco and then hit I-35 up to my parents' in Oklahoma City. Along the way, I enjoyed another non-Dominican cigar and cranked the tunes.
Since I've been in OKC, I've made the most of it.</description></item><item><title>My Epic 17 Mile Run &amp; Other Moderately Fascinating Stuff</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/20/my-epic-17-mile-run-other-moderately-fascinating-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/20/my-epic-17-mile-run-other-moderately-fascinating-stuff/</guid><description>I haven't blogged for about three weeks! While I have the occasional reader, I don't think anyone's had to deal with a huge hole in their lives as a result of my absence. I could blame it on the heat or the fact that we're now more than halfway through the year and I've taken a total of one day of vacation so far. But I guess I don't have any real reason other than I just didn't feel like it.</description></item><item><title>STP Concert Videos</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/01/stp-concert-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/01/stp-concert-videos/</guid><description>The Stone Temple Pilots concert this past Saturday ROCKED! See my videos on YouTube for proof, you skeptics. I didn't see them "back in the day" so it was great to finally get the chance. Only two things could have made it better - new songs (where are they, guys?) and reasonable prices for beer (they were $10 for a 24 oz Shiner). But as I said before, I'm not much of a ranter so I'll leave it at that.</description></item><item><title>Vinyl LP Record Is 60 Years Old Today</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/21/vinyl-lp-record-is-60-years-old-today/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/21/vinyl-lp-record-is-60-years-old-today/</guid><description>I just got an email from Sound Stage Direct, one of my favorite online record stores, which said the vinyl LP record is 60 years old today (invented June 21, 1948 by Peter Goldmark). I searched good ol' YouTube and found the video below which does a good job of providing some history about the format as well as some insight into how exactly records are made. Very interesting...</description></item><item><title>Mates of State Concert &amp; Restaurant Stuff</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/15/mates-of-state-concert-restaurant-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/15/mates-of-state-concert-restaurant-stuff/</guid><description>Jamie I saw Mates of State this past Thursday at Warehouse Live. I've really been digging their new album, Re-Arrange Us and it was my first time to see them live. For only two people, their unique combination of keyboard, drums, and vocal harmony makes for a nice, full sound. I picked their latest up on vinyl, which overflowed my record collection into its 2nd crate.
Here's a video I took of "</description></item><item><title>French Kicks Show, New Records, and a 10 Mile Run</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/08/french-kicks-show-new-records-and-a-10-mile-run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/08/french-kicks-show-new-records-and-a-10-mile-run/</guid><description>Once again, I packed a lot of fun into the weekend. Jamie and I went to the French Kicks concert at Walter's on Friday night with some friends. Houston's own Young Mammals (formerly The Dimes) opened and made me a fan almost instantly. It was my second time to see the French Kicks and they put on a great show yet again.
I took it easy Saturday. I got a humidor for some quality cigars I recently procured and then paid another visit to my music mecca, Cactus Records.</description></item><item><title>Shampoo for My Shaved Head &amp; A Lesson in the Metric System</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/05/shampoo-for-my-shaved-head-a-lesson-in-the-metric-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/05/shampoo-for-my-shaved-head-a-lesson-in-the-metric-system/</guid><description>Today I stopped by my local Sport Clips to get some more shampoo. Yes, even shaved heads need to be washed with quality shampoo. Trust me, it's that much more important when people can see every inch of your scalp. I go with the Paul Mitchell Tea Tree stuff. At first, I liked it for the tingly sensation, but I guess my head is way too cool for that now because I don't feel a thing when I use it.</description></item><item><title>The Flying Tomato</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/02/the-flying-tomato/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/02/the-flying-tomato/</guid><description>Yes, it's been over a week yet again since my last post. If I actually had some readers, this would be a bad thing. But since I don't, I guess it doesn't really matter much. If anyone does read this drivel, please leave a comment so I can feel good about myself. Actually, I don't need anyone to make me feel good about myself, but it would be nice to know you're reading this.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on 30</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/07/thoughts-on-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/07/thoughts-on-30/</guid><description>As I'm staring down 30 (tomorrow at 7:01 pm Central to be exact) I should probably blog about how awful it is, but now that it's inevitable, I really don't think it's all that scary. I pretty much act like I'm six as often as I can. I've worn one of my favorite t-shirts, a He-Man ringer, for years. I just recently picked up a 'Vote Optimus 08' Transformers t-shirt, too.</description></item><item><title>Camping @ Pace Bend &amp; A New Personal Record For Downhill Speed!</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/04/camping-pace-bend-a-new-personal-record-for-downhill-speed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/04/camping-pace-bend-a-new-personal-record-for-downhill-speed/</guid><description>I had a great time camping this weekend with some friends at Pace Bend Park next to Lake Travis, TX. For the most part, we just hung out enjoying tasty beer (Saint Arnold's Lawnmower/Summer Pilsner/Amber and Sierra Nevada Pale Ale for you connoisseurs), a fine Cuban cigar, and the perfect weather. One of the highlights of the trip for me was setting a new personal record for downhill speed on our 35 mile bike ride around the lake.</description></item><item><title>Up at 6:00 am on a Saturday...</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/19/up-at-600-am-on-a-saturday.../</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/19/up-at-600-am-on-a-saturday.../</guid><description>So I'm up at 6:00 am on a Saturday morning about to go meet some friends for a bike ride. We'll be doing at least 25 miles, but maybe 50 if we feel up for it. Crazy I know, but there's a certain excitement around getting up early, eating a carbolicious breakfast, drinking some coffee, and hitting the road for awhile. My only real complaint is how much gear is involved in a simple bike ride.</description></item><item><title>Son Volt with Bobby Bare Jr. @ The Continental Club, Negativland @ Rice's Aurora Picture Show</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/18/son-volt-with-bobby-bare-jr.-the-continental-club-negativland-rices-aurora-picture-show/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/18/son-volt-with-bobby-bare-jr.-the-continental-club-negativland-rices-aurora-picture-show/</guid><description>I caught a couple of great shows the past two days. Wednesday night, I went to see Son Volt at The Continental Club. For those who are not familiar with the band, Jay Farrar the lead singer/song writer, was previously in Uncle Tupelo (forefathers of the "No Depression"/alt-country genre) and one of my favorite bands - Wilco. There was a bit of a falling out between him and Jeff Tweedy during the recording of the epic "</description></item><item><title>All the cool kids are doing it</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/15/all-the-cool-kids-are-doing-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/15/all-the-cool-kids-are-doing-it/</guid><description>Here goes my foray into proper blogging. I decided to do this for several reasons.
I used to enjoy writing until years of composing corporate email took their toll on my once sharp literary wit. Sometimes I think I live in my head too much. I could probably benefit from attempting to organize my thoughts in a coherent manner on a regular basis. It seems like a good way to let people know what's going on in my life without running the risk of repeating the same story to the same people over and over.</description></item></channel></rss>