<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/</link><description>Recent content on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:24:19 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top Albums of 2024</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2024/12/21/top-albums-of-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:24:19 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2024/12/21/top-albums-of-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the year when &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com">Advent of Code&lt;/a> has gotten too elfing hard and I use what&amp;rsquo;s left of the year&amp;rsquo;s productive energy to publish my list of favorite albums.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I discovered a few new artists/groups this year, but an AI trained only on previous years&amp;rsquo; lists could have correctly guessed half of these:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Ty Segall - Three Bells&lt;/strong> Another batch of perfectly baked psych pop/rock from a longtime favorite. I saw him play yet again at the Gothic Theatre back in May.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2023</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2023/12/22/top-albums-of-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 17:17:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2023/12/22/top-albums-of-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d do more with a prestigious domain name like &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org">andydyer.org&lt;/a> than post a list of my favorite albums once a year. Someday, perhaps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This year I included several albums from 2022. I listened to them so many times that it felt weird to exclude them solely based on their release date.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>DoMi &amp;amp; JD Beck - NOT TiGHT (2022)&lt;/strong> Instant favorite. So good! The classic jazz influences are woven throughout. Does that arpeggio sound like something from Coltrane? Giant Steps-like for sure. Did Herbie Hancock inspire that track? Probably, he&amp;rsquo;s playing on it! They combine virtuosity with a nod to the past while sounding entirely unique.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>La Colonie de Vacances - ECHT (2022)&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.musicglue.com/la-colonie-de-vacances/about">Four bands&lt;/a> at the same time! The chaos is surprisingly organized. After listening to it loudly, enough times to get past the initial shock, I came appreciate what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. Undoubtedly, sitting in the middle of these bands in a live setting would be the best way to hear this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Billy Woods &amp;amp; Kenny Segal - Maps&lt;/strong> Rich lyrics anchor this album from the MC who &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Billywoods/comments/o3lplf/re_the_blurred_face/">values his privacy&lt;/a>. Make sure the Mike&amp;rsquo;s right like Phil Jackson in &amp;lsquo;96.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Czarface - Czarmageddon (2022)/Czartificial Intelligence (2023)&lt;/strong> Comic book rap from Wu-Tang&amp;rsquo;s Inspectah Deck &amp;amp; friends. A perfect skateboard video/pickup basketball game/chill soundtrack.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Osees - Intercepted Message&lt;/strong> They evolve their sound despite it seeming impossible to continue doing so after all this time. Whether they are covering hold music or evoking the best of Devo, I will dutifully add every one of their albums to my end-of-year lists.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>GOAT - Medicine&lt;/strong> Check out &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RNMuGxuJuv0">this live set&lt;/a> for a taste of their psych-rock magic.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>MJ Lenderman - Boat Songs (2022)/And the Wind (Live and Loose, 2023)&lt;/strong> Catchy throwback indie rock from the Wednesday guitar player. I gave this several listens on a Midwestern road trip over the summer. It felt right among the cornfields.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Feeble Little Horse - Girl with Fish&lt;/strong> They evoke the fuzzy loud/quiet/loud 90s indie rock sound I love (a perennial theme, I know).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wednesday - Rat Saw God&lt;/strong> - Shoegaze plus a steel guitar and slice of life lyrics.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Nat Myers - Yellow Peril&lt;/strong> To the blues what Charley Crockett is to country, although that&amp;rsquo;s an oversimplification. I was a fan as soon as I heard his voice on top of the guitar. Also successfully road trip/ramblin&amp;rsquo; tested.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with a song from each of the above albums:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2022</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2022/12/27/top-albums-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 14:43:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2022/12/27/top-albums-of-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year&amp;rsquo;s top albums list is a mix of chill &amp;amp; aggressive, ranging from folky Americana, to psych rock, and even punk. While past favorites Kendrick Lamar &amp;amp; Earl Sweatshirt both released long-awaited albums, I did not find myself returning to them the way I did with their previous releases.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This list is probably the first that has included a new mix of an album that was released in a different year (The Beatles - Revolver), but I think it sounds so modern, its inclusion is defensible. And it&amp;rsquo;s my list, so my rules, right?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2021</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/12/24/top-albums-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 10:09:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/12/24/top-albums-of-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year I said farewell to Berlin, road tripped around southern Germany, and moved to sunny Colorado. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of favorite albums that soundtracked it all:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Mdou Moctar - Afrique Victime&lt;/strong> My first concert in over a year and a half, Mdou Moctar did not disappoint. While the guitar playing is undoubtedly the feature, be sure to appreciate the skill of the drummer as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Night Beats - Outlaw RnB&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Night Beats fan &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/">for years&lt;/a> but until this album, I was convinced I preferred the psych rock of their first couple albums over their more recent soul/R&amp;amp;B sound. This one grew on me more with each listen. They also released a great album of acoustic versions of these tracks and did a Levitation Sessions. I included a track from the latter on the playlist below.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fuzz - Levitation Sessions&lt;/strong> Just about any Levitation Sessions release makes for a great listen; most definitely this one. There was also a nice &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V9o_P9hKQGk">Part II of the OSees Levitation Sessions&lt;/a> released this year, but I resisted the urge to include it after having three of their albums on &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/22/top-albums-of-2020/">last year&amp;rsquo;s list&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fruit Bats - Siamese Dream&lt;/strong> Siamese Dream is one of my all-time favorite albums. This cover album chills everything out and does every track well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Buck Meek - Two Saviors&lt;/strong> I surprised myself by how often I kept coming back to the Big Thief guitar player&amp;rsquo;s second solo album. There&amp;rsquo;s so much detail in the lyrics and the melodies are catchy enough to hum to yourself once they infect your subconscious.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Floatie - Voyage Out&lt;/strong> Floatie immediately reminded me of Palm, another math-rock favorite of mine. I&amp;rsquo;ve praised their label, &lt;a href="http://www.explodinginsoundrecords.com/">Exploding in Sound Records&lt;/a>, more than once over the years and Floatie is another good example of the kind of sound I like to have exploding in my vicinity.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Meatbodies - 333&lt;/strong> Does this sound an awful lot like Fuzz? Yes, and that&amp;rsquo;s precisely why I like it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Na$ty - The Rodez Tapes&lt;/strong> While we patiently await new Kendrick &amp;amp; Earl Sweatshirt albums, Na$ty was a new discovery for me that scratches a similar hip-hop itch. Boasts like &amp;ldquo;So ahead of my time I wrote this rhyme last week&amp;rdquo; flow effortlessly over laid-back lo-fi beats. Dig it.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Charley Crockett - 10 for Slim &amp;amp; Music City USA&lt;/strong> This year gave us a couple batches of new-but-retro-sounding country songs from Mr. Crockett. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see him live, but tickets are over $100 each! Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get a copy of each on vinyl and some good whiskey for a night in instead.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wednesday - Twin Plague&lt;/strong> There&amp;rsquo;s always something shoegazey on this list and Wednesday fills that role this year. Droning, swooping, fuzzed out guitars alternating in a loud/quiet dynamic. Yep, this&amp;rsquo;ll do nicely.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with a song from each of the above albums:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spoiling the Dark plot with Kotlin</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/05/01/spoiling-the-dark-plot-with-kotlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 09:01:11 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/05/01/spoiling-the-dark-plot-with-kotlin/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>As promised in &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/21/building-a-family-tree-dsl-with-jetpack-compose-syntax/">my last post&lt;/a>, it&amp;rsquo;s time to use our family tree DSL to spoil the plot of &lt;a href="https://dark.netflix.io">Netflix&amp;rsquo;s Dark series&lt;/a>! ðŸ˜ˆ&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To quickly recap, we have a small but functional (my puns are always intended) DSL for building a family tree in Kotlin:&lt;/p>
&lt;script src="https://gist.github.com/abdyer/c838ebb995850c1fab59f43c9cefeb35.js">&lt;/script>

&lt;h3 id="the-dark-family-trees-in-code">The Dark family trees in code&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The family trees are of course the focus of the series as they are revealed to us piecemeal; episode by episode, season by season. After watching it, I was overwhelmed with all the details and quickly gave up trying to fit it all together. Sure, I remembered some of the bigger points, but it makes a lot more sense after stepping through the &lt;a href="https://dark.netflix.io">Dark website&lt;/a> to build the family trees below:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Building a Family Tree DSL with Jetpack ComposeÂ syntax</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/21/building-a-family-tree-dsl-with-jetpack-compose-syntax/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 20:05:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/21/building-a-family-tree-dsl-with-jetpack-compose-syntax/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Originally published on &lt;a href="https://proandroiddev.com/building-a-family-tree-dsl-with-jetpack-compose-syntax-fe652ce6cb0f">ProAndroidDev&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="why-build-a-dsl">Why build a DSL?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Ever since first getting into Kotlin, I&amp;rsquo;ve known it has a few things that makes building domain-specific languages (DSLs) easier. I&amp;rsquo;ve read the mind-expanding &lt;a href="https://kotlinlang.org/docs/type-safe-builders.html">type-safe builders&lt;/a> guide for building a DSL for HTML, but until recently I hadn&amp;rsquo;t found a good use case for building a DSL of my own.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://jobs.zalando.com/en/jobs/2986308-senior-android-engineer-appcraft-mobile">My team at Zalando&lt;/a> maintains server-driven UI libraries for Android &amp;amp; iOS that power completely dynamic screens such as home, brand homes, collections, and various landing pages in the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.zalando.mobile">Zalando fashion&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://apps.apple.com/de/app/zalando-fashion-shopping/id585629514?l=en">store apps&lt;/a>. Often, we need to build mock responses during development for new features that don&amp;rsquo;t have a backend implementation yet or models for unit tests. In the past, we&amp;rsquo;d grab chunks of JSON from API responses and edit them, but navigating a wall of text is tedious and editing JSON is far less fun than writing code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flexbox Layout Behavior in Jetpack Compose</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/16/flexbox-layout-behavior-in-jetpack-compose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 10:31:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/16/flexbox-layout-behavior-in-jetpack-compose/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Originally published on the &lt;a href="https://engineering.zalando.com/posts/2021/03/flexbox-layout-behavior-in-jetpack-compose.html">Zalando Engineering Blog&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://drafts.csswg.org/css-flexbox-1/">CSS Flexible Box Layout specification&lt;/a> (AKA flexbox) is a useful abstraction for describing layouts in a platform agnostic way. For this reason, it is widely used on the web and even &lt;a href="https://github.com/google/flexbox-layout">on mobile&lt;/a>. Readers familiar with &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/androidx/constraintlayout/widget/ConstraintLayout">&lt;code>ConstraintLayout&lt;/code>&lt;/a> can think of flexbox as conceptually similar to the &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/androidx/constraintlayout/helper/widget/Flow">&lt;code>Flow&lt;/code>&lt;/a> virtual layout it supports. This type of layout is ideal for grids or other groups of views with varying sizes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2020</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/22/top-albums-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 12:02:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/22/top-albums-of-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p>This year was full of unexpected surprises, disappointments, and more for everyone, but music was here to comfort us throughout. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of favorite albums for the year:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Hum - Inlet&lt;/strong> Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s talked music with me long enough has heard me express my adoration for Hum. They were the first/one of the first &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/">bands I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live&lt;/a>. Their particular brand of space rock/shoegaze/whatever-you-want-to-call-it has always been one of my favorites. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long couple decades since their last release, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4VY15Q2_NU">Downward Is Heavenward&lt;/a>, so I was skeptical whether this year&amp;rsquo;s surprise new album would greet these old ears the same as their earlier releases. It took a few listens for me to warm up to it, but this album is certainly one of my top picks for the year.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>OSees - Protean Threat&lt;/strong> Their name has yet another new spelling and the kraut/prog rock evolution of their sound continues. Longsuffering readers of my top albums lists will recall my love of this band, so no surprise to see them on this year&amp;rsquo;s list again (although I did not include &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of the albums they released this year). This one works so well as an end-to-end listen that I listened to it a second time in a row on more than one occasion.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>OSees - Levitation Sessions&lt;/strong> Until this year, every summer in Berlin meant an OSees tour stop and a guaranteed great night out. Luckily, the band shared this live recording that serves as a decent surrogate, but you probably won&amp;rsquo;t be showered by thrown beers in your living room.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>OSees - Metamorphosed&lt;/strong> Oh, the audacity of including a third album from the same band on a top 10 list! You may not be surprised to learn that there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href="https://thehardtimes.net/music/even-newer-thee-oh-sees-album-somehow-released-new-thee-oh-sees-album/">Hard Times article&lt;/a> poking fun at the frequency of their album releases. This one is some leftover tracks from last year&amp;rsquo;s Face Stabber double album; a couple short ones and a couple extended jams doing what they do best.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Run the Jewels - RTJ4&lt;/strong> Listening to the hard-hitting lyrics of this album, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget that it was penned before the Black Lives Matter protests erupted earlier this year. That&amp;rsquo;s because systemic racism is nothing new as Mike &amp;amp; El-P so eloquently convey on track after track. Have you ever taken a moment to &amp;ldquo;look at all these slave masters posing on your dollar&amp;rdquo;? It&amp;rsquo;s pretty messed up when you think about it. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://99percentinvisible.org/article/fact-follows-fiction-real-bridges-based-euro-banknote-artwork/">the EU has bridges on their currency&lt;/a> as a symbol of connection, ju$t saying. RTJ also did a live stream of their performance of the entire album. Mike&amp;rsquo;s acapella verse at the end of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FUvoQrcsETg">Walking in the Snow&lt;/a> is intense!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fuzz - III&lt;/strong> While there was no new Ty Segall album this year, the third release from his Fuzz side project gives us a chance to hear him play drums and sing. This time there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of Thin Lizzy-esque guitar harmonies and other new sonic elements to add some color to the Sabbath sludge they so effortlessly conjure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Charley Crockett - Welcome to Hard Times&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/zvie5df0SP8?t=65">&amp;ldquo;Do you like sinnin&amp;rsquo;? Well, you will before you go.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> is all the invitation I needed to enter Charley&amp;rsquo;s classic country time machine. The Davy Crockett descendant croons about love and heartbreak while reminding us that the telephone used to play a central role in the game.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Khruangbin - Mordecai&lt;/strong> The Houston trio has continued to explore the funk elements of their sound, which adds some swagger to any walk or cleaning session. I love the quirky adventurousness of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oc50wHexbwg">Time (You and I) video&lt;/a>. And since &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W9YNkE_JOhA">Christmas Time Is Here&lt;/a>, check out their version of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4PzetPqepXA">Vince Guaraldi song&lt;/a> from A Charlie Brown Christmas.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Kurt Vile - Speed, Sound, Lonely KV&lt;/strong> After enjoying 2018&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bottle It In&amp;rdquo; and seeing his show here in Berlin last year, I was happy to see a new EP from Kurt Vile this fall. After several listens, I learned from the &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/163479981/our-show">All Songs Considered podcast&lt;/a> that there are a couple John Prine songs on it, including a thought-provoking duet with Prine on &amp;ldquo;How Lucky&amp;rdquo;, which recalls a visit to places of our past and what we are lucky enough to remember (or forget). If you are not very familiar with the late great John Prine, the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZXgZGrVlL4">original&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kHTmXFfhjz8">versions&lt;/a> of these two songs are a great place to start.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Jimi Hendrix - Live in Maui&lt;/strong> As evidenced by numerous other choices on the list, I clearly needed fuzzy guitars and extended jams in high doses this year. I&amp;rsquo;ll end with yet another glimpse into the mastery of Jimi Hendrix. This release covers a pair of concerts the rock legend performed on the side of a dormant volcano in 1970. Watch some of the video to see Jimi make guitar wrangling look easy and timelessly cool. Also, laugh at the tripping hippies waving their hands in front of their far out faces.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with a song from each album, but I assure you there are many more you really should hear. Let me know if you find a new favorite or have something else to recommend!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jetpack Benchmark on Firebase Test Lab</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/03/06/jetpack-benchmark-on-firebase-test-lab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Mar 2020 10:30:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/03/06/jetpack-benchmark-on-firebase-test-lab/</guid><description>&lt;p>As previously outlined in my &lt;a href="http://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/22/appcraft-faster-than-a-speeding-release-train/">talk at Mobius Conference&lt;/a> in Saint Petersburg last year, our team at Zalando is building a server-driven UI platform we call AppCraft. AppCraft allows us to add or update screens in &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.zalando.mobile">our app&lt;/a> with only server changes instead of the normal app release constrained way of doing things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the client side, we are building every screen the same way: fetch layout &amp;amp; data from the server, parse it, and render it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2019</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/23/top-albums-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 17:47:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/23/top-albums-of-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>Time files and it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s been several years since I &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/">last shared&lt;/a> my favorite albums of the year. Despite the lack of posts, I still keep a list every year and decided it&amp;rsquo;s time once again to highlight some of the albums I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed most:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Oh Sees - Face Stabber&lt;/strong> Any year that includes an Oh Sees release will find it &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/">in my top albums list&lt;/a>, so here it is. I also &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/">see them anytime their tour comes through town&lt;/a>. Again, no exception this year. The band continues its exploration of prog rock while still retaining just enough of their psych rock foundation to sound unmistakably like themselves.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Chris Staples - Holy Moly&lt;/strong> Not to be confused with the much more country-fied &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4zAThXFOy2c">Chris Stapleton&lt;/a>, Chris Staples is a new discovery for me this year. I&amp;rsquo;d describe him as indie singer/songwriter with a strong Wilco sensibility. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing him here in Berlin next month.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ty Segall - Deforming Lobes (Live), First Taste&lt;/strong> Similar to the Oh Sees guarantee above, Ty Segall &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/">always&lt;/a> makes the year&amp;rsquo;s top albums list as well. This year, the prolific psych rocker gave me two albums to love; a live album and the &lt;a href="https://pitchfork.com/reviews/albums/ty-segall-first-taste/">notably guitarless&lt;/a> &amp;ldquo;First Taste&amp;rdquo; (although it&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe some of these sounds aren&amp;rsquo;t guitars).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wilco - Ode to Joy&lt;/strong> Wilco is another perennial favorite of mine. Jeff Tweedy&amp;rsquo;s songwriting is as strong as ever and this album is one that deepens a bit with each listen.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Versing - 10000&lt;/strong> A wonderful recreation of that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2Nsy4h8rD4">Pavement&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AVtskhcGOtc">Built to Spill&lt;/a> slacker rock sound with a dash of Nirvana style grunge. All the ingredients for a good album.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Spoon - Everything Hits at Once (Best Of)&lt;/strong> Spoon is another of my favorites that makes &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/">any year&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> top albums list. This is a &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; spanning most of their albums, with the disappointing absence of a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IVOvxT5GZi8">killer track&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rCgfLSuf2O8">two&lt;/a> from &amp;ldquo;Series of Sneaks&amp;rdquo;. Nevertheless, the track order is great and this collection should serve as a solid introduction for anyone as yet unfamiliar with their greatness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Khruangbin - Hasta El Cielo&lt;/strong> Painfully known to me as the band I missed seeing last year due to a calendar time zone mixup, Khruangbin released a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dub_music">dub&lt;/a> version of their wonderful &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9cN1XCpfWD4">&amp;ldquo;Con Todo El Mundo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> album. I love how the different style further mellows what was already a pretty laid back sound. Perfect for a rainy Sunday morning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ari Roar - Best Behavior&lt;/strong> Bouncy guitar and bass lines that remind me of bands like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=59cQWw9ctOA">Pinback&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VKJkq-fuFKU">Palm&lt;/a> paired with breezy vocals. Soundtrack a windows-down-stereo-up car ride with this.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>(Sandy) Alex G - House of Sugar&lt;/strong> Introspective and at times haunting lyrics softened with acoustic guitar &amp;amp; a sprinkle of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HcO-NPtj5BI">lo-fi wooze&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dead Soft - Big Blue&lt;/strong> I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for 90s guitar rock like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxlfkFMjLZc">early Weezer&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sNfocDNZWY8">Matthew Sweet&lt;/a>. Dead Soft does this well.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>AppCraft: Faster Than a Speeding Release Train</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/22/appcraft-faster-than-a-speeding-release-train/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 16:45:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/22/appcraft-faster-than-a-speeding-release-train/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was a pleasure speaking at &lt;a href="https://mobius-piter.ru/en/">Mobius Conference&lt;/a> in Saint Petersburg this past May. I never got around to finishing the transcript of the talk I intended to write, but you can find the slides on &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/abdyer/appcraft-faster-than-a-speeding-release-train">Speaker Deck&lt;/a> and the video on &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xo45nwRxtik&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;t=20">YouTube&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;p/>
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xo45nwRxtik?start=20" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe></description></item><item><title>Introducing Biografy</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/12/24/introducing-biografy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 20:53:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/12/24/introducing-biografy/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-is-biografy">What is Biografy?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.biografy">Biografy&lt;/a> is a lifelogging app that automatically builds a timeline of each day. The &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/events.png">&lt;em>Events&lt;/em>&lt;/a> view logs events from various apps including music, podcasts, videos, calls and chats. Each event includes rich detail such as the time, activity (stationary, walking, biking, etc.), and location/place. The &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/motion.png">&lt;em>Motion&lt;/em>&lt;/a> view lists car/transit trips, bike rides, runs, and walks. With the &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/map.png">&lt;em>Map&lt;/em>&lt;/a> view, you can see where you were when each event occurred and gain insights like where you spend your time based on the clusters of pins. Finally, the &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/notes.png">&lt;em>Notes&lt;/em>&lt;/a> view is perfect for adding context to remember each day. Want to travel back in time? Simply tap the toolbar to choose the date.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>React Native: Is It Worth It?</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/11/27/react-native-is-it-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 21:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/11/27/react-native-is-it-worth-it/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="intro">Intro&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>When new technologies start gaining momentum in the Android community, the pragmatic (or lazy) among us eventually have to ask ourselves, â€œIs it worth it?â€ After the initial arrival and departure of the hype train, some of these become trusted tools we use in almost every app. Think &lt;a href="https://github.com/ReactiveX/RxJava">RxJava&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://google.github.io/dagger/">Dagger&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://facebook.github.io/react-native/">React Native&lt;/a> may be on its way to earning a place in the same club. Once we get past the fact that JavaScript on Android and HTML in JavaScript seem pretty damn weird at first, thereâ€™s a lot to like. Seeing your changes on a device almost instantly is a love-at-first-sight kind of thing. And rethinking your app architecture as a series of actions, state changes, and UI render phases can eliminate a surprising number of silly bugs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things I've Learned Since Moving to Berlin</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 12:45:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/east_side_gallery_sunset.jpg" alt="East Side Gallery Sunset" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; display: block" />
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Berlin for a bit more than six months now. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It is possible to survive a summer without air conditioning. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to go all summer without a mosquito bite.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t miss having a car. Public transit is great here so I typically only need one to haul things like furniture. And I can rent one on demand pretty easily with apps like &lt;a href="https://www.drive-now.com/de/en">DriveNow&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I really enjoy bicycling to work, but don&amp;rsquo;t ride for fun as much.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can take beer almost anywhere. The only downside is you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to take the bottles back. It&amp;rsquo;s an endless cycle. They&amp;rsquo;re worth â‚¬0.08 each and it&amp;rsquo;s not cool to throw them away in your building&amp;rsquo;s bins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You need less stuff than you think. No, even less than that. There were a lot of things we moved but didn&amp;rsquo;t use or have room for. This same philosophy applies to daily life in Berlin. Not having a car means carrying what you need with you. &amp;ldquo;Do I really need this jacket?&amp;rdquo; is a good question to ask yourself if it&amp;rsquo;s going to warm up later in the day. At first, I carried a backpack with my laptop, etc. to/from work on the bike, but leaving things in a locker at work proved to be a liberating alternative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can order cocktail supplies from Amazon. You can also get them at the grocery store or even at a spÃ¤ti if you are willing to pay a bit more for the convenience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The paperwork thing is for real. Without fail, I am always in the middle of some bureaucratic battle involving paperwork, waiting, mailing more paperwork, and waiting some more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I thought the cluster of buildings Google Maps showed as the BÃ¼rgeramt were abandoned based on &lt;a href="https://igx.4sqi.net/img/general/width960/lO8a2iJHE8snO4Du7k9Ok4isx-N3rYfnvTwq-wkQF0M.jpg">the plant life&lt;/a>. I turns out that they just don&amp;rsquo;t mow/trim things very often. Efficiency?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Every so often, someone on public transit will surprise you with &lt;a href="https://www.thelocal.de/20151211/19-weird-things-you-can-do-on-the-berlin-tube">something crazy&lt;/a> after you thought you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it all.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Things they don&amp;rsquo;t have here: garbage disposals (you dispose or organic waste in a dedicated bin), right turn on red (more about this below), stop signs at every intersection (the rightmost person goes first if there are multiple vehicles), overly attentive waiters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Obey the traffic signals. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason most Germans wait patiently for traffic signals even when there is no opposing traffic coming. The Polizei will eventually get you if you don&amp;rsquo;t. I stopped before going right on red while biking and some police on bikes came out of nowhere to cut me off and stop me. I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure from my still fledgling German skills, but I think I have a ticket coming in the mail for that soon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You don&amp;rsquo;t need German very often until you need it. Older people often speak less English and some government officials seem to stick to it even when they know you&amp;rsquo;re struggling. I&amp;rsquo;ve gradually gotten less embarrassed about trying, but I still mess up daily. It&amp;rsquo;s humbling but rewarding as I slowly progress.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before moving here I knew Berlin had techno on an endless loop in clubs every weekend. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that some clubs occasionally have daytime parties, which means I can spend a couple hours there during my son&amp;rsquo;s nap. #dadlife&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People get really excited about seasonal produce here. And for good reason, it&amp;rsquo;s delicious! You will know what&amp;rsquo;s in season by suddenly seeing it EVERYWHERE. &lt;a href="https://www.rnz.de/cms_media/module_img/297/148685_1_org_14910200C55C0C85.jpg">Asparagus&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://foodieinberlin.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/l1040042.jpg">strawberries&lt;/a>, and chanterelle mushrooms have been some of my favorites so far.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the US, we call the sport &amp;ldquo;soccer&amp;rdquo; and table game &amp;ldquo;foosball&amp;rdquo;. In Germany, they call the sport &amp;ldquo;fuÃŸball&amp;rdquo; (fussball) and the table game &amp;ldquo;kicker&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Skinny(ier) jeans are functional as well as fashionable. For example, looking cool while not getting your jeans caught in your bike chain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People either stare at you or don&amp;rsquo;t notice you at all. Either way, you can be yourself without caring what anyone else thinks. Someone is always weirder than you.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I love this city even more than I thought I would. I remind myself every day how fortunate I am to live here.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Aufwiedersehen, Houston! Hallo, Berlin!</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 13:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anyone who has talked to me for more than 10 minutes has probably heard me mention my love for Berlin. I first visited the city about six years ago and almost immediately resolved to make it my home one day. I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to finally announce that &lt;a href="https://media.giphy.com/media/rl0FOxdz7CcxO/giphy.gif">it&amp;rsquo;s happening&lt;/a>! I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining &lt;a href="https://tech.zalando.com/">Zalando&lt;/a> in Berlin next month to do &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.zalando.mobile&amp;amp;hl=en">Android&lt;/a> and hopefully step up my fashion game a bit. &lt;a href="http://www.redherring.com/features/radical-agility-zalando-tech-become-berlins-hottest-engineering-ticket/">Radical Agility&lt;/a> sounds like engineering nirvana to me! After working remotely for the past year and a half, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being in an office again, especially one where I&amp;rsquo;ll get to work with smart people from all over the world.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Multiple Developers, One App: How to Not Break Everything</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/10/22/multiple-developers-one-app-how-to-not-break-everything/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 13:00:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/10/22/multiple-developers-one-app-how-to-not-break-everything/</guid><description>&lt;p>This was my third time attending the Big Android BBQ in Hurst, TX and my third time to present at it. Perhaps my favorite thing about the conference (aside from the obvious BBQ) is reconnecting with old friends and making new ones. This year I&amp;rsquo;ve had the pleasure of meeting people from all over the world and learning that we know a lot of the same people. Small world, indeed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things That Suck About Android Development</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/03/18/things-that-suck-about-android-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 13:17:48 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/03/18/things-that-suck-about-android-development/</guid><description>&lt;p>I presented &amp;ldquo;Things That Suck About Android Development&amp;rdquo; at this year&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://mdevcon.com/">mdevcon&lt;/a> conference in Amsterdam. It&amp;rsquo;s a great conference in an amazing city. I highly recommend it to anyone developing mobile apps.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The title is admittedly a bit sensational, but my goal was to highlight many of the painful parts about developing for Android and how to avoid/fix them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The slides are available &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/abdyer/things-that-suck-about-android-development">here on Speaker Deck&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2015</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late with my annual Top 10 list, but here it is roughly ranked by Google Music play count:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Earl Sweatshirt - I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Shit, I Don&amp;rsquo;t Go Outside&lt;/strong> I was finally lucky enough to &lt;a href="http://www.houstonpress.com/music/earl-sweatshirt-revels-in-raps-odd-future-at-warehouse-live-7746980">see him live&lt;/a> and he didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint. Another great release. This soundtracked numerous skateboard and chill sessions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Vince Staples - Summertime &amp;lsquo;06&lt;/strong> His &amp;ldquo;Hell Can Wait&amp;rdquo; EP made my list last year and I knew this one would be on this year&amp;rsquo;s list right away. The subject matter is heavy, but you may be nodding your head so much at first you won&amp;rsquo;t notice. I recommend multiple listens so you can fully appreciate both its depth and undeniable crunkness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Drumcode - A-Sides Volume III&lt;/strong> Ever since getting bitten by the techno bug, I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a solid list of podcasts I listen to regularly like &lt;a href="http://www.droidbehavior.com/blog/podcast/">Droid Podcast&lt;/a> and Adam Beyer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://drumcode.se/">Drumcode Radio (DCR)&lt;/a>. This collection of Drumcode singles includes many that were feature on DCR.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Fuzz - II&lt;/strong> This Ty Segall side project returns with another face melting set. For when you want to rock. Hard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ryan Adams - 1989&lt;/strong> I had successfully avoided knowingly hearing any of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s album until I heard this song-for-song cover album from the prolific Mr. Adams. Now I realize they&amp;rsquo;ve been plaguing my every shopping experience for months. But there&amp;rsquo;s no way around it, these are good songs. I contend they&amp;rsquo;re even better with Ryan Adams performing them.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Panda Bear - Panda Bear Meets the Grim Reaper&lt;/strong> For the uninitiated, Panda Bear is a member of Animal Collective, a pretty kick ass indie psych band. This is his fifth solo album. Reverb, chants, and a masterful combination of Eastern &amp;amp; electronic instruments pay tribute to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lD4sxxoJGkA">Pet Sounds&lt;/a> and beyond.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Buxton - Half a Native&lt;/strong> Houston&amp;rsquo;s Buxton delivers an album of honest and heartfelt songs. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, but when Sergio Trevino sings about shyly introducing himself to a woman in &amp;ldquo;Pool Hall&amp;rdquo;, you feel like you &lt;em>are&lt;/em> there.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Deerhunter - Fading Frontier&lt;/strong> Bradford Cox and crew continue their legacy of jangly rock songs that are hard to categorize, but always sound like Deerhunter.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Car Seat Headrest - Teens of Style&lt;/strong> I owe this discovery to NPR All Songs Considered&amp;rsquo;s coverage of the CMJ Music Festival. The young Will Toledo&amp;rsquo;s bedroom recordings confirm he has another great album coming when he records in a proper studio in 2016.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Wilco - Star Wars&lt;/strong> This Wilco album came out of nowhere&amp;hellip;no press coverage, no teased release date&amp;hellip;just a free download on the interwebz. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s another Wilco album, but one that I enjoyed a bit more than their last two.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLiOTTgupZ1CBE0OdDyg1jOfQpwr0VlbA9">Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist&lt;/a> with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Using a Third Party FAB with CoordinatorLayout</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/28/using-a-third-party-fab-with-coordinatorlayout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/28/using-a-third-party-fab-with-coordinatorlayout/</guid><description>&lt;p>Before the Design Support Library was announced at Google I/O last month, I had numerous third party libraries in my projects for various elements of Material Design. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed replacing the nav drawer, tabs, and parallax scrolling libraries with their support library counterparts. However, on one of my projects, we needed an expanding floating action button (FAB) similar to the one in &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.inbox">Inbox&lt;/a>, which the support library does not currently provide.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Time I Interviewed at Google</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/09/the-time-i-interviewed-at-google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/09/the-time-i-interviewed-at-google/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a pretty big secret for the past month or so; something that only my friends and family know about. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, sneaking around interviewing for a new job like we&amp;rsquo;re having an affair. Only this time, it was different. As an Android developer, this was like trying out for the majors. No&amp;hellip;seriously, y&amp;rsquo;all&amp;hellip;Google invited me to interview.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My adventure started early last month as I was triaging my inbox. There were the usual spammy recruiter emails seeking &amp;ldquo;rock stars&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;ninjas&amp;rdquo; with skills in technologies I abandoned years ago. I skimmed what appeared to be another of these and stopped when I read &amp;ldquo;mobile is a huge priority for us here at Google&amp;rdquo;. Did I read that correctly? Apparently I did. Where did this come from? The domain was google.com. &lt;a href="http://cdn.meme.am/instances/500x/54979149.jpg">For real tho&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Loading a List of Objects from Firebase</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/04/06/loading-a-list-of-objects-from-firebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/04/06/loading-a-list-of-objects-from-firebase/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with &lt;a href="https://www.firebase.com/">Firebase&lt;/a> lately in preparation for adding data synchronization to my &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary">Music Library&lt;/a> app. Their &lt;a href="https://www.firebase.com/docs/android/quickstart.html">docs&lt;/a> did a great job of getting me set up. Using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/firebase/firebase-login-demo-android">sample app&lt;/a> as a guide, I even got Google+ OAuth working without much trouble. From there, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to load data into a Firebase instance partitioned by Google account. All that was left was to query the data out of Firebase and I&amp;rsquo;d be able to see the sync magic in action.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I'm Unironically Carrying This Small, Older Android Phone</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p>I thoroughly enjoyed my last night in Berlin a little over a week ago; so much that I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice my phone was missing until the end of the night. Shake your head and say it couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen to you. I thought the same thing until it did. Normally, I keep my phone in one of my front pockets, but I was wearing a coat that covered the pocket, making it a bit more difficult to grab my phone quickly to check Google Maps. Since my coat has a side access pocket in the chest, I stowed my phone there while walking around. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing a skillful thief at the last bar spotted my phone in that side pocket and was able to slide it out without me knowing. I was in a crowded room and often looking to one side as I talked to different people. Self-shaming thoughts aside, sometimes it happens.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>MCE Conference 2015 - Automated Testing for Modern Android Applications</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/08/mce-conference-2015-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/08/mce-conference-2015-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p>It was an honor to speak at and attend &lt;a href="http://mceconf.com/">MCE Conference&lt;/a> in Warsaw last week. I participated in a workshop where I learned about prototyping with Android and Arduinos. I attended talks about Groovy, Kotlin, Proguard, design, scaling apps for emerging markets, and some handy new libraries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That alone easily makes MCE one of the best conferences I&amp;rsquo;ve been to. On top of all that, the networking with fellow speakers and attendees was a personal highlight. To everyone I met, I hope to stay in touch until our paths cross again. And I hope you caught up on your sleep!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Running Shell Commands with Gradle and a Better Way to Delombok</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/01/22/running-shell-commands-with-gradle-and-a-better-way-to-delombok/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/01/22/running-shell-commands-with-gradle-and-a-better-way-to-delombok/</guid><description>&lt;p>A few months ago, I &lt;a href="http://andydyer.org/blog/2014/09/29/delombok-and-javadoc-with-gradle/">posted&lt;/a> about how to use Gradle tasks to &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://projectlombok.org/features/delombok.html">delombok&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; code using Lombok annotations before generating Javadocs. My solution for running the delombok task used Ant and was based on what I found after the requisite Google &amp;amp; StackOverflow searching. This worked just fine until Android Studio 1.0 and the associated Gradle build tools were released at the end of the year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The crux of the problem appeared to be a change in the way dependencies are merged during compilation. Countless &amp;ldquo;package does not exist errors&amp;rdquo; were causing the delombok task to fail. I first attempted to solve this by changing the way the classpath was built in the task. While I was able to reduce the number of errors, I didn&amp;rsquo;t succeed in completely fixing the problem. All the while, running the delombok task directly from the command line with &lt;code>java -jar build-libs/lombok.jar delombok src -d build/src-delomboked&lt;/code> ran successfully.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2014</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p>The end of another year means it&amp;rsquo;s time for the annual Top 10 Favorite Albums list.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Ty Segall - Manipulator&lt;/strong> While not the leader in sheer track plays via my Google Play Music account, this album is perfect all the way through. It certainly spent a lot of time on my turntable as well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Nothing - Guilty of Everything&lt;/strong> A wonderful example of the specific brand of rock music I love. Heavily &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zhxXn60Z0yk">MBV&lt;/a> influenced wall of sound guitars. They were almost deafeningly loud when I saw them at &lt;a href="http://fitzlivemusic.com">Fitzgerald&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a> over the summer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Whirr - Sway&lt;/strong> One of the members of Nothing also founded Whirr. As you might expect, they have a similar sound. Similarly awesome.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Sturgill Simpson - Metamodern Sounds in Country Music&lt;/strong> Like a modern day &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=14ZHn_76QM0">Waylon Jennings&lt;/a>. While I&amp;rsquo;m not a big country fan, I can appreciate honest, heartfelt songs. These are.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Spoon - They Want My Soul&lt;/strong> Such a consistent band. Their sound evolves slightly with each album, yet they always sound like Spoon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Meatbodies - Meatbodies&lt;/strong> Ty Segall&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iDEmMyowfPU">Fuzz&lt;/a> band mate Chad Ubovich also helms Meatbodies. Psych rock, fuzz, reverb, etc. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DuYOMvTLoJo">Thee Oh Sees&lt;/a>/Ty Segall type rock n&amp;rsquo; roll.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Parquet Courts - Sunbathing Animal&lt;/strong> Their slacker rock sound reminds me a bit of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lPvhKV3Yg2k">Pavement&lt;/a>. Simple yet catchy songs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cheatahs - Cheatahs&lt;/strong> On par with the Nothing and Whirr albums on the list, more fuzzy droning shoegaze-y goodness.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Schoolboy Q - Oxymoron&lt;/strong> I continued exploring hip-hop this year and this album led the pack. &amp;ldquo;Los Awesome&amp;rdquo; is like a modern day &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uWbXQQG9B6c">California Love&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_L2vJEb6lVE">Collard Greens&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; features Kendrick Lamar and name checks Houston. And more. What else do you need?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Vince Staples - Hell Can Wait&lt;/strong> Vince Staples has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BGfE-mbdmXg">collaborated with Earl Sweatshirt&lt;/a> (whose &amp;ldquo;Doris&amp;rdquo; album was on my list last year) and toured this year with Schoolboy Q. Apparently my ear is also finely tuned for a specific style of hip-hop. Whatever the case, this album will get your head nodding if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I made a YouTube playlist with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Music Library 3.0 - Material Design Update</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/11/02/music-library-3.0-material-design-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/11/02/music-library-3.0-material-design-update/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/music_library_icon.png" alt="Music Library" style="width: 150px; float: left; margin-right: 20px" />
I started developing [Music Library](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary) about four years ago when I wanted an app for organizing my record collection. Armed with my Nexus One, Eclipse, and a copy of Apress' [Pro Android](http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430246804/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1430246804&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=slacod-20&amp;linkId=FMLK73AOGDPPJEM3), I spent my nights and weekends learning the inner workings of my now-favorite mobile OS.
&lt;p>Over the years, Music Library has been a playground of sorts for exploring various open source libraries, patterns, and best practices. While there is still a fair amount of code I would write differently today (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, ContentProvider), the app has been and continues to be an enjoyable side project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>BABBQ5 - Automated Testing for Modern Android Applications</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/17/babbq5-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/17/babbq5-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my third year to attend and present at the &lt;a href="http://www.bigandroidbbq.com/">Big Android BBQ&lt;/a>. &lt;a href="http://news.bigandroidbbq.com/2014/09/speaker-spotlight-andrew-dyer.html">My talk&lt;/a> this year showed how to prepare an Android app for automated testing using mocking, dependency injection, and Google&amp;rsquo;s super fast Espresso test runner. You can find the presentation on &lt;a href="https://speakerdeck.com/abdyer/babbq5-automated-testing-for-modern-android-applications">Speaker Deck&lt;/a> and the sample code on &lt;a href="https://github.com/abdyer/android-test-demo">GitHub&lt;/a>.
&lt;br/>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hosting Android Dependencies on GitHub</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/05/hosting-android-dependencies-on-github/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/10/05/hosting-android-dependencies-on-github/</guid><description>&lt;p>As I mentioned in my &lt;a href="http://andydyer.org/blog/2014/09/29/delombok-and-javadoc-with-gradle/">last post&lt;/a>, I&amp;rsquo;m developing an SDK at work. The libraries I use most frequently in my apps are all included as Maven dependencies. Adding a line to my &lt;code>build.gradle&lt;/code> file is much preferred to downloading a JAR file. To make the SDK as easy as possible for developers to include in their projects, I wanted to deliver it the same way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://central.sonatype.org/">Maven Central&lt;/a> is the de facto repository for open source library hosting. Since the SDK I&amp;rsquo;m developing is part of a product and as such will not be open source, I needed to find another place to host the binary that would still allow it to be included via Maven.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Delombok and Javadoc with Gradle</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/09/29/delombok-and-javadoc-with-gradle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/09/29/delombok-and-javadoc-with-gradle/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently had my first experience working with Javadoc to generate documentation for an SDK I&amp;rsquo;ve been developing at work. In general, I&amp;rsquo;m in the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://blog.codinghorror.com/coding-without-comments/">clean code doesn&amp;rsquo;t need comments&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; camp, but SDKs tend to be a limited view into a larger abstraction, so good documentation is a necessity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Javadoc has been around since the introduction of the Java language, so I won&amp;rsquo;t include a primer here. If you want to learn more, &lt;a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/javase/documentation/javadoc-137458.html">Oracle has you covered&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Android's Material Design and The Bauhaus</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/13/androids-material-design-and-the-bauhaus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/13/androids-material-design-and-the-bauhaus/</guid><description>&lt;p>Since Android Gingerbread (v2.3), loyalists know that each version has an Easter egg that can be accessed by repeatedly tapping the version number on the Settings &amp;gt; About screen. The Android &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo; Preview is no exception.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While test driving the new version, I naturally had to see what Google had hidden for me in their latest release. Previous versions have had everything from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PeAFCIvqNxc">gingerbread zombies&lt;/a> to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DfY73GBBHxg">Nyandroids&lt;/a> and a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iN-nJdAJS7g">pile of jelly beans&lt;/a>. The Android &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo; Preview build has a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_He5MIYJas8">simple animation of random overlapping red and blue rectangles&lt;/a>. Several Android blogs mentioned this, but dismissed it as &lt;a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/android-l-Previews-easter-egg-webdriver-torso">mysterious&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="http://www.slashgear.com/hands-on-with-the-android-l-features-google-didnt-mention-27335613/">strange&lt;/a>. While these random rectangles are clearly the same used by Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27778071">WebDriver Torso&lt;/a> YouTube video quality testing, so far everyone seems to have missed the most obvious explanation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Fun with Android Wear</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/12/fun-with-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/12/fun-with-android-wear/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/deutschuhr_androidwear.png" alt="Deutsch Uhr" style="width: 140px; float: left; margin-right: 20px" />I got my &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/devices/details?id=lg_g_watch_black">LG G Android Wear&lt;/a> smart watch earlier this week and dove right into developing for it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My first project was &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.deutschuhr">Deutsch Uhr&lt;/a>, a text-based German language watch face inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.mypebblefaces.com/apps/1446/1484/&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHn1MUA0IUtwhRwqFGHYKorEIcmLg">my favorite Pebble watch face&lt;/a>. I had fun adding animations for the hour/minute/day changes and learning what makes a Wear app tick (pun intended, I always do). A big thanks to my friend Daniel Ward for help getting started. Be sure to check out his &lt;a href="http://phandroid.com/2014/07/06/custom-android-wear-watch-faces-binary-clock/">Binary Watch Face&lt;/a>, which was the first Android Wear watch face to appear on Google Play a couple weeks ago.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Google I/O 2014: An Android Developer's Perspective</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/06/28/google-i/o-2014-an-android-developers-perspective/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/06/28/google-i/o-2014-an-android-developers-perspective/</guid><description>&lt;p>This yearâ€™s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wtLJPvx7-ys">Google I/O&lt;/a> developer conference once again gave developers plenty to be excited about. As expected, we heard about the next release of the Android operating system, Android Wear smart watches, and updated development tools. Rumored products &amp;amp; services such as Android TV, Android Auto, and Google Fit were also announced. Perhaps the most exciting and far-reaching announcement was the new Material Design language, which replaces the now dated looking Holo with a consistent look for all platforms. Enterprise users can now securely separate work &amp;amp; personal data with the Android Work suite of services. Finally, Android Cardboard showed us how to make a DIY version of an Oculus Rift style VR headset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Droidcon Berlin 2014: Froyo to KitKat</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/05/09/droidcon-berlin-2014-froyo-to-kitkat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/05/09/droidcon-berlin-2014-froyo-to-kitkat/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to be speaking at Droidcon Berlin this year. I fell in love with the city on my first visit and the conference was a perfect reason for another visit. Attempts to try out my very basic German skills have shown me that I have a long way to go. However, I am proud to say that I have managed to make a few purchases without panicking and falling back to English.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Developing for Android Tutorial</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/04/04/developing-for-android-tutorial/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/04/04/developing-for-android-tutorial/</guid><description>&lt;p>I gave a two hour tutorial on developing for Android at work today for our weekly tech talk. Similar in style to my coworker &lt;a href="http://aaronortbals.com/">Aaron Ortbals&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://github.com/aortbals/ember-github-example">tutorial on Ember.js&lt;/a>, I showed how to build a client for &lt;a href="https://developer.github.com/v3/activity/events/">GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Events API&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Topics included:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Project setup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Gradle dependencies&lt;/li>
&lt;li>API requests &amp;amp; JSON parsing&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Activities &amp;amp; fragments&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Lists, adapters, and custom item layouts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>You can find the source code and the slides for the tutorial &lt;a href="https://github.com/abdyer/android-intro">on GitHub&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Presenting: Wrist Presenter for Android and the Pebble Smartwatch</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/03/07/presenting-wrist-presenter-for-android-and-the-pebble-smartwatch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/03/07/presenting-wrist-presenter-for-android-and-the-pebble-smartwatch/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/wristpresenter_icon@2x.png" alt="Wrist Presenter" style="width: 150px; float: left; margin-right: 20px" />
Shortly after getting a Pebble Smartwatch this past Christmas, my coworker and all-around-cool-dude [Matthew Morey](http://matthewmorey.com/) asked me if I'd be interested in developing the Android version of his [Wrist Presenter iOS app](http://matthewmorey.com/wrist-presenter/). Luckily, he already had a rock solid Pebble app developed, so I didn't have to flex my meager C programming skills.
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://wristpresenter.com/">Wrist Presenter&lt;/a> turns your Pebble Smartwatch into a remote for presentations running on your Android or iOS device.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing Kollektor</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="why-a-new-app">Why a new app?&lt;/h5>
&lt;p>When I first decided to get into Android development, I created the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary">Music Library&lt;/a> app to catalog my vinyl collection. It served me well as I learned the ins and outs of Android programming including &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/providers/content-providers.html">content providers&lt;/a>, interacting with other applications via &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Intent.html">intents&lt;/a>, working with the file system to save/load images, making API requests, etc. In order to test the workings of the Android app market, I published the ad supported Music Library Free and the paid Music Library versions of the app. In addition to not displaying ads, Music Library also included the ability to backup your collection to the device&amp;rsquo;s SD card and export data to a Google Drive spreadsheet.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2013</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each year, I keep a list of albums that I find myself listening to frequently. This is the time of year when I review the list and pick my top 10. I ventured into hip-hop and electronic music a bit more this year. Psych rock and 90s style fuzz are also well represented.&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UUc5y1NljXI">My Bloody Valentine - MBV&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YjgEBZhsGJs">Disclosure - Settle&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmpOntxlbcY">Swearin&amp;rsquo; - Dust in the Gold Sack&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eHoKMZf8M0">Weed - Deserve&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLsq8zPvloY">Thee Oh Sees - Floating Coffin&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TPCtrybEt8E">Night Beats - Sonic Bloom&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xfsXK9Lgitk">Speedy Ortiz - Major Arcana&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGEx8SfI540">Unknown Mortal Orchestra - II&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dg0yfie121E">Waxahatchee - Cerulean Salt&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FCbWLSZrZfw">Earl Sweatshirt - Doris&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item><item><title>Signing Volley Requests with Scribe</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/15/signing-volley-requests-with-scribe/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/15/signing-volley-requests-with-scribe/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I initially needed to integrate OAuth request signing with &lt;a href="https://android.googlesource.com/platform/frameworks/volley">Volley&lt;/a> in my Android app, I used the &lt;a href="https://code.google.com/p/oauth-signpost/">Signpost library&lt;/a>. It was fairly straightforward to build a URL, pass it to the Signpost OAuthConsumer, and retrieve a new string with the appropriate OAuth parameters added. Unfortunately, as you can see from the &lt;a href="https://github.com/mttkay/signpost/commits/master">commit history&lt;/a>, there has been very little activity over the past year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Increasingly, I see recommendations for &lt;a href="https://github.com/fernandezpablo85/scribe-java">Scribe&lt;/a>. The project is very active and it makes &lt;a href="https://github.com/fernandezpablo85/scribe-java/wiki/getting-started">implementing OAuth request signing&lt;/a> as easy as it&amp;rsquo;s likely to get.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TechStreet Houston: Intro to Android Programming</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/11/20/techstreet-houston-intro-to-android-programming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/11/20/techstreet-houston-intro-to-android-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m giving another Intro to Android Programming talk at &lt;a href="http://www.techstreethouston.com/">TechStreet Houston&lt;/a> today. The slides are very similar to my previous talk at Houston TechFest, but &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1r6jf2VPOETDOR7TcFGw_qPymbYOEfmaDGC5v2Hib31o/edit?usp=sharing">here is the link&lt;/a> for today&amp;rsquo;s presentation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Things I Learned at Big Android BBQ 2013</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/13/things-i-learned-at-big-android-bbq-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/13/things-i-learned-at-big-android-bbq-2013/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>T-Mobile reception is still terrible at the conference center.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Alcohol purchases spike in the City of Hurst as a result of the conference.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The guys from &lt;a href="http://www.willowtreeapps.com/">Willow Tree Apps&lt;/a> have released some awesome Android open source libraries (&lt;a href="https://github.com/derekbrameyer/android-betterpickers">BetterPickers&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://github.com/willowtreeapps/OAK">OAK&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/JonathanNye/rpatch">RPatch&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It&amp;rsquo;s worth the short drive to &lt;a href="http://rootscoffeehouse.com/north-richland-hills/">Roots Coffee&lt;/a> each morning.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.highrollerusa.com/shop/">High Roller&lt;/a> makes adult size big wheels. They are a ton of fun to ride.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="http://en.oppo.com/">Oppo&lt;/a> makes some pretty sweet phones. Their &lt;a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/9/23/4762618/oppo-n1-announced-cyanogenmod-android-rotating-camera">N1 will ship with&lt;/a> &lt;a href="http://www.cyanogenmod.org/">CyanogenMod&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I wish I had signed up for the &lt;a href="http://www.google.com/glass/start/how-to-get-one/">Google Glass Explorer&lt;/a> program.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/112937922652870132700">Daniel Ward&lt;/a> bears a &lt;a href="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-y68HoUyN5-Y/Uln1HvB7fRI/AAAAAAAARcw/D--lqBnDrJg/w852-h474/daniel-obiwan.jpg">strong resemblance&lt;/a> to Ewan McGregor&amp;rsquo;s Obi Wan Kenobi.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Google makes Android. Anyone who attended the closing keynote/panel will understand why this is funny.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://plus.google.com/111558319297322546031">Ray Walters&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a> BBQ: OMG. So good!&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Agile is dead. Liquid will soon be the new hotness. More on this later.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I thoroughly enjoyed the conference once again this year. I highly recommend it to anyone who has anything to do with Android.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Big Android BBQ 2013 - Android Open Source Libraries You Need in Your Life</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/11/big-android-bbq-2013-android-open-source-libraries-you-need-in-your-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/10/11/big-android-bbq-2013-android-open-source-libraries-you-need-in-your-life/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is my second year to speak at the &lt;a href="http://www.bigandroidbbq.com/">Big Android BBQ&lt;/a> in Hurst, TX. My talk covered a slew of handy open source libraries to accelerate the development of modern Android applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The slides are available on &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/file/d/0B7Daz4FEcG6Dbkx2RGVjYTNvaUE/edit?usp=sharing">Google Drive&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m having a blast at the conference. The sessions so far have been great. I hope to see all of you here again next year!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Houston TechFest: Intro to Android Programming</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/09/28/houston-techfest-intro-to-android-programming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/09/28/houston-techfest-intro-to-android-programming/</guid><description>&lt;p>I gave an Intro to Android Programming presentation today at &lt;a href="http://www.houstontechfest.org/SitePages/Home.aspx">Houston TechFest&lt;/a>. The slides are available on &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/1q3m7_DjXpoPtIzOA5eci8JLLeNnwGsTQRrd7Aj8TofM/edit?usp=sharing">Google Drive&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks to everyone who attended. Keep Android trill!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Migrating from Ant to Gradle</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/08/06/migrating-from-ant-to-gradle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/08/06/migrating-from-ant-to-gradle/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a talk on migrating a custom Eclipse/Ant build to Android Studio/Gradle at &lt;a href="http://www.meetup.com/Houston-Android-Developers/events/132350872/">tonight&amp;rsquo;s Houston Android Developers meetup&lt;/a>. The slides are available on &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/15TekbzLYvs1bfAgpRx_2yWsA_il1HPEIkFR-mNmPlSc/edit?usp=sharing">Google Drive&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I hope to see you there!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Surprised this domain was available</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/07/14/surprised-this-domain-was-available/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/07/14/surprised-this-domain-was-available/</guid><description>&lt;p>I finally got around to registering a domain name and setting up a basic &lt;a href="http://octopress.org/">Octopress&lt;/a> site. I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting here about music/code/coffee/beer/life releated stuff when the mood strikes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Setting item selected state in Android GridView</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/09/25/setting-item-selected-state-in-android-gridview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/09/25/setting-item-selected-state-in-android-gridview/</guid><description>&lt;p>
 When working with the GridView in an Android app recently, I ran into a very strange behavior around setting the
 selected state for a view created in my ArrayAdapter's getView() method. Â I'm using selectors to handle the drawable
 states and everything works properly when tapping a list item to select/tapping again to unselect. Â When debugging
 the ArrayAdapter's getView() method, I could see that the selected state was being set to the correct value when
 calling view.setSelected(), but the button background was not updated to the proper state.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Functional Queue in JavaScript</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/02/03/a-functional-queue-in-javascript/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2012/02/03/a-functional-queue-in-javascript/</guid><description>&lt;p>
	It's been over a year since I've posted here, but I've been busy delving into Android and Ruby on Rails among other
	things. To get back into blogging (hopefully more regularly...we'll see), I thought I'd share an interesting
	JavaScript exercise I was asked to complete as part of a job interview recently.
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
	The task was to build a functional queue in JavaScript. Â A functional queue is a queue (first in, first out) which
	is implemented with no side-effects. Â For instance, a function to enqueue a value onto an existing queue will return
	a new object which represents the larger queue. Â The original (smaller) queue is still available.
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Top 10 Albums of 2010</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/12/28/my-top-10-albums-of-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/12/28/my-top-10-albums-of-2010/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Since I put together my inaugural Top 10 list last year, I may as well make it a tradition. Luckily I had the
 foresight to keep a running list in &lt;a href="http://www.evernote.com/">Evernote&lt;/a> throughout the year, so the
 tough part was putting them in order. Some may argue about the order of the albums on the list or the exclusion of
 others. I'd love to hear your opinions.&lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>So without any further &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Eisa5AZ20W0">jibba jabba&lt;/a>, here's my Top 10
 Albums of 2010 list:&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>
 &lt;ol>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Gorilla-Manor-Local-Natives/dp/B0032IAB4C/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593217&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Local
 Natives - Gorilla Manor&lt;/a>&lt;/b> The harmonies are amazing. I saw these guys twice this year and
 loved both shows.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Flaming-Stardeath-Dwarfs-Rollins-Peaches/dp/B003D8O8FY/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593246&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Flaming
 Lips - Dark Side of the Moon&lt;/a> &lt;/b>I was lucky enough to see the Lips perform this on &lt;a
 href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/01/02/my-review-of-flaming-lips-new-years-eve/">NYE 2009 in OKC&lt;/a>. A great cover
 of a great album.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Brothers-Black-Keys/dp/B003AO1SVS/ref=sr_1_1?s=music&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593281&amp;amp;sr=1-1">The
 Black Keys - Brothers&lt;/a>&lt;/b> I listened to this album over and over this past summer. Nice
 gritty bluesy rock.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Odd-Blood-Yeasayer/dp/B0030E5NKU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593310&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Yeasayer
 - Odd Blood&lt;/a>&lt;/b> Another band I saw live this year. Upbeat indie rock to enliven any task or
 workout.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Astro-Coast-Surfer-Blood/dp/B002ZPIBG8/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593332&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Surfer
 Blood - Astro Coast&lt;/a>&lt;/b> Surf rock sound thanks to lots of Telecaster but new and different
 at the same time. Plus a song about &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000186/">David Lynch&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Say-Born-Ruffians/dp/B003A2HXAK/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593352&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Born
 Ruffians - Say It&lt;/a>&lt;/b> I saw these guys play at the &lt;a
 href="http://blogs.houstonpress.com/rocks/2010/09/i_want_this_place_to.php">newly reopened
 Fitzgerald's&lt;/a> in my 'hood. Great live show. Catchy album.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Transference-Spoon/dp/B002VDZIIS/ref=sr_1_1?s=music&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593396&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Spoon
 - Transference&lt;/a>&lt;/b> Few bands consistently release great albums while gradually morphing
 their sound. Spoon does. Another constant listen this past year.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/King-Beach-Wavves/dp/B003SNYZVG/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593414&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Wavves
 - King of the Beach&lt;/a>&lt;/b> The summer of 2010 was a brief indie surf rock renaissance. Or maybe
 I'm discounting a trend with a longer shelf life. But I'm no critic. Good album for the beach. Or kings
 of them.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Wild-Smile-Suckers/dp/B003HLT0BO/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593441&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Suckers
 - Wild Smile&lt;/a>&lt;/b> These guys toured with Local Natives and the first time I heard them was
 when they opened that show. Bad ass tunes kinda like Local Natives but not. Apples and oranges, but
 still fresh &amp;amp; delicious organic fruit (I may have yuppied that fruit part up a bit, but oh well).
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>&lt;a href="http://giantprincess.blogspot.com/p/merch.html">Giant Princess - Zip Zop Wow&lt;/a>&lt;/b> Awesome
 new band from the H Tizzle. Raucous indie rock. Saw them do an in store at my beloved &lt;a
 href="http://twitter.com/#!/cactus_music">Cactus Music&lt;/a> and dug it.&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ol>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Things To Do While I'm on Vacation in December</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/11/22/things-to-do-while-im-on-vacation-in-december/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/11/22/things-to-do-while-im-on-vacation-in-december/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 I didn't take much of my vacation time this year, so I'm left with thirteen days of vacation to take in December. In
 an effort to make the most of this bounty of time off, I made a list of things to do. Thanks to Jamie for suggesting
 I make a list after patiently enduring my first couple brainstorming sessions.&lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>Here's the list in no particular order:&lt;br />
 &lt;div>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>Triumphant return to homebrewing - &lt;/b>Brew an American Pale Ale. Cascade hops and more Cascade
 hops.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>"Fixing a hole where the rain gets in..." - &lt;/b>Patch a couple small leaks in the garage roof.
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>No clever way to say it - &lt;/b>Rake some leaves.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>Dining reconnaissance at Stella Sola - &lt;/b>One of the few local restaurants I haven't tried yet.
 &lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>Mini "Into the Wild" camping trip - &lt;/b>Solo camping for a few days with my guitar and mountain
 bike. Maybe Huntsville State Park.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>These are the (An)droids you're looking for - &lt;/b>Finally finish developing the Android
 application I've been working on sporadically over the past several months.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>Save me from my phone, Phone - &lt;/b>Build a Windows Phone 7 equivalent of my Android application.
 Given the far superior development tools available for WP7, this should be a much quicker build than
 the Android app.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>Eat, drink, and be merry - &lt;/b>Celebrate the most wonderful time of the year with family and
 friends.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>Put the needle on the record - &lt;/b>Put on some headphones, lay on the floor, and enjoy my record
 collection.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;b>"Take a look, it's in a book..." - &lt;/b>Decide which book I want to read next and spend some time
 turning pages.&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Indie Rock Mix CD for My Canada/Montreal Trip</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/07/07/indie-rock-mix-cd-for-my-canada/montreal-trip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/07/07/indie-rock-mix-cd-for-my-canada/montreal-trip/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Any good trip needs a soundtrack. With this in mind, I created a mix CD with the following tracks. All of the bands
 except where noted hail from Montreal or at least Canada. I've included links to listen to the tracks on YouTube. No
 Celine Dion or Bryan Adams will be found here, only the coolest indie bands Canada has to offer.&lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>These are in no particular order. I know, I know... the art of a good mix is in the song order, but I plan to
 put the CD on shuffle in the rental car to let chance determine what we hear when:&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>
 &lt;div>
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CMSVCKsHRks">Of Montreal - An Eluardian Instance&lt;/a> (Not
 FROM Montreal, but it's in their name)&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J6Ppc_4Be5o">Built to Spill - Hindsight&lt;/a> (Not FROM
 Canada, but the lyric "What about Canada? It's paradise. It's pines and ice." makes me chuckle every
 time I hear it.)&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EcDYMpQlFLA">Arcade Fire - Month of May&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lb9WKJhqVWs">Broken Social Scene - World Sick&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=56_MTZDXwZU">Hot Hot Heat - Middle of Nowhere&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ABhrrytjL_E">Wolf Parade - Ghost Pressure&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mqIHptgTam0">Islands - Rough Gem&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hpvqU2cmK8I">New Pornographers - Use It&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iRZ_SWA_SbA">Postal Service - Mushaboom&lt;/a> (Remix of the
 Feist song. She's from Canada.)&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MkMIxJrrz10">Tokyo Police Club - Breakneck Speed&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QyDPUaW6kwA">Born Ruffians - Foxes Mate for Life&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AZW9NYX6JZA">St Vincent - Actor Out of Work&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yq_tDOFU5tY">Caribou - Odessa&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U8KAU9vWGgc">Tegan &amp;amp; Sara - Back in Your Head&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jOoHAbnhxNI">Japandroids - Young Hearts Spark Fire&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qLVIsbLy_5Q">AC Newman - Palace at 4 AM&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xnnuGZ3QKgM">Sunset Rubdown - Idiot Heart&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3mIZooCIQ3o">The Unicorns - Jellybones&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>My review of The Flaming Lips' "New Year's Eve Freakout"</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/01/02/my-review-of-the-flaming-lips-new-years-eve-freakout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/01/02/my-review-of-the-flaming-lips-new-years-eve-freakout/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Since my friend Greg asked for it, here's a review of The Flaming Lips' "New Year's Eve Freakout" as their latest
 album, "Embryonic", spins on the turntable.&lt;br />&lt;br />The last time I saw the Lips was in high school just after
 the release of "Clouds Taste Metallic". That experience and word-of-mouth since prepared me for the celebratory
 chaos that is a Flaming Lips show. &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/JoeMathlete"> Joe Mathlete&lt;/a> of &lt;a
 href="http://www.29-95.com/">29-95.com&lt;/a> did &lt;a
 href="http://www.29-95.com/time-suck/story/my-flaming-lips-new-year%E2%80%99s-eve-extravaganza-part-one">a very
 entertaining set of cartoons&lt;/a> documenting his trip to OKC for the show accurately described a Flaming Lips
 concert as "the biggest happiest birthday party ever, and everyone in the room is turning six".&lt;br />&lt;br />The
 biggest draw for me was the fact that the Lips &lt;a
 href="http://pitchfork.com/news/37233-flaming-lips-to-cover-pink-floyds-idark-sidei-live-on-new-years-eve/">would
 be playing Pink Floyd's "Dark Side of the Moon" at midnight&lt;/a>. The week before the concert, they released the
 studio version of the album. I debated for less than five minutes whether I should listen to it or wait to hear it
 live on New Year's. Of course, I caved and listened to it repeatedly. I love how they made it their own, even
 completely changing the vibe of some songs like "Breathe" so that I had to really focus to hear what my ears were
 used to hearing from the Floyd version. Similarly, the clocks at the beginning of "Time" and the cash register/coins
 sound collage at the beginning of "Money" were changed (ha ha ha, pun intended) up quite a bit. I also appreciated
 that Henry Rollins was tapped for the speaking parts interspersed throughout the album. For my American English
 trained ears, this was the first time I was able to understand some of the speaking parts without the veil of a
 thick British English accent.&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/Sz-qJlVag-I/AAAAAAAAAFs/GSHn8jMtq5E/s1600-h/IMG_5912+%28Small%29.JPG">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 300px;"
 src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/Sz-qJlVag-I/AAAAAAAAAFs/GSHn8jMtq5E/s400/IMG_5912+%28Small%29.JPG"
 alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5422239557994841058" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />Back to the concert itself... We
 wisely got a room at the Renaissance Inn across the street from the convention center to avoid the need to drive
 anywhere. Some friends and friends of friends joined us at the hotel before the show for a little preparty. Around
 10pm, we walked across the street to the convention center. The Flaming Lips had just gone on stage and proceeded to
 play a mixture of old and new songs including "Do You Realize?", "Convinced of the Hex", "She Don't Use Jelly", and
 "Yoshimi Battles the Pink Robots".&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/Sz-qi43hWAI/AAAAAAAAAF0/eixmY94O6AA/s1600-h/IMG_5928+%28Small%29.JPG">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 300px;"
 src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/Sz-qi43hWAI/AAAAAAAAAF0/eixmY94O6AA/s400/IMG_5928+%28Small%29.JPG"
 alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5422239992734898178" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />Big balloons in a variety of colors
 bounced among the crowd and my eyes noticed a sea of such balloons occupying the seats behind the stage. "Why aren't
 these balloons being enjoyed?", I wondered. I decided to do my part and throw as many of the balloons as possible
 into the part of the crowd where we were sitting. This was much appreciated by those around us, but was quickly
 interrupted by the yelling of stagehands below. It was then I realized these balloons were for midnight. My bad,
 dudes.&lt;br />&lt;br />At midnight, the aforementioned idle balloons were swept into the crowd, resulting in a sea of
 multicolored balloons reminiscent of the ball pit at Showbiz Pizza. After (or before, I'm not sure), Wayne came out
 with giant hands and shot green lasers into the large hemispherical disco ball in the center of the arena. The disco
 ball refracted the lasers everywhere and prepared us for the Flaming Lips/Pink Floyd masterpiece we were about to
 witness.&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/Sz-qxcyulSI/AAAAAAAAAF8/N_x6u1R12so/s1600-h/IMG_5995+%28Small%29.JPG">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer; width: 400px; height: 300px;"
 src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/Sz-qxcyulSI/AAAAAAAAAF8/N_x6u1R12so/s400/IMG_5995+%28Small%29.JPG"
 alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5422240242896639266" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />Before they started playing Dark
 Side, Wayne asked all of us to set the alarm on our phones for 12:55 AM with whatever sound was currently set, which
 was obviously when they planned to launch into "Time". No cuckoo clocks with gears and chimes in 2010; this would be
 interesting.&lt;br />&lt;br />Their performance of Dark Side for the most part stuck to the studio version, but hearing it
 live and seeing a seemingly endless sea of costumed characters such as a whale in a captain's uniform dancing at the
 sides of the stage made it even better. I really enjoyed watching Steven scream the diva part from "The Great Gig in
 the Sky" into a distorted megaphone. The Pink Floyd version of that song always gives me chills and The Flaming Lips
 version is no different. I also loved when they said "And now, we begin Side 2" in the middle of the performance.
 Time to flip the record, kids... We were sitting on the left side of the stage and I didn't see Henry Rollins, but
 heard his speaking parts throughout the set. Were they using a recording of him? Maybe someone with a different
 vantage point can clear that up for me.&lt;br />&lt;br />Overall, it was a great New Year's Eve. No one was shoving past
 me to get to a bar and I didn't have to listen to the clucking of drunk girls in extra short cocktail dresses. I
 didn't have to drive, and I didn't have to talk to any police officers.&lt;br />&lt;br />If you haven't ever listened to
 Pink Floyd's "Dark Side of the Moon", SHAME ON YOU! Go get a turntable, the record, and a good set of headphones.
 Then, let me know how wonderful it is. After 100 or more listens, treat yourself to the Flaming Lips version. Which
 reminds me, I still need to listen to that with headphones...&lt;br />&lt;br />Here are a few videos:&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;span
 style="font-weight: bold;">Convinced of the Hex&lt;/span>&lt;br />&lt;object width="425" height="344">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/tfpVusIfIsY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">
 &lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always">&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/tfpVusIfIsY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"
 allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425"
 height="344">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;">Yoshimi Battles the Pink
 Robots&lt;/span>&lt;br />&lt;object width="425" height="344">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/3QtVUKVWlWE&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">
 &lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always">&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/3QtVUKVWlWE&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"
 allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425"
 height="344">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;span style="font-weight: bold;">Money (Pink Floyd
 cover)&lt;/span>&lt;br />&lt;object width="425" height="344">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/UUSBHVH21Jo&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">
 &lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always">&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/UUSBHVH21Jo&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;fs=1&amp;amp;" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"
 allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Bands I've Seen Live</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 09:12:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking for quite some time about trying to compile a list of all the bands I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ll put these in order as much as possible. I plan to keep adding to this as I recall past shows and attend more in the future. I have a ticket stub book, so I&amp;rsquo;ll include the dates and other details for those I have. Some of these are special in that the bands have since split up, are no longer touring, and/or some members have passed away. You can find videos from a lot of these shows on my &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/dammitandy">YouTube&lt;/a> channel. Here we go:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Happiness is a byproduct</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/01/05/happiness-is-a-byproduct/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/01/05/happiness-is-a-byproduct/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 The "Quote of the Day" on my Google homepage must repeat every year, because I'm sure I've seen this one before.
 Â Nevertheless, it's so true:&lt;div>
 &lt;blockquote>Happiness is always a by-product. It is probably a matter of temperament, and for anything I know it
 may be glandular. But it is not something that can be demanded from life, and if you are not happy you had
 better stop worrying about it and see what treasures you can pluck from your own brand of unhappiness.&lt;br />
 - &lt;a href="http://www.quotationspage.com/quote/31739.html">Robertson Davies&lt;/a>&lt;/blockquote>&lt;a
 href="http://www.quotationspage.com/quote/31739.html">&lt;/a>&lt;br />
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>My latest adventures</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/11/08/my-latest-adventures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/11/08/my-latest-adventures/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Again, too long between blog posts. Â My faithful readers are clammoring for more of my adventures. Â Right? Â Well,
 most likely not, but here it goes...&lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>First, Jamie and I went to the &lt;a href="http://www.aclfestival.com/default.aspx">ACL Festival&lt;/a> in Austin
 about a month ago. Â It was the first time to go for both of us and we saw a ton of great bands including &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/vampireweekend">Vampire Weekend&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/bobbybarejr">Bobby Bare Jr&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/matesofstate">Mates of State&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/jennylewismusic">Jenny Lewis&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/theold97s">Old 97's&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/josegonzalez">Jose
 Gonzalez&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/drivebytruckers">Drive-By Truckers&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/canseidesersexy">Cansei de ser Sexy (CSS)&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/mgmt">MGMT&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/conoroberst">Conor Oberst&lt;/a>,
 and &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/beck">Beck&lt;/a>. Â Here's a video I took of Beck doing "Hell Yes":&lt;/div>
 &lt;div style="text-align: center">&lt;br />&lt;object width="425" height="344">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/GPbJGz5RL7s&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">
 &lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always">&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/GPbJGz5RL7s&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"
 allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>Check out the rest of the videos I took &lt;a
 href="http://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=dammitandy+acl&amp;amp;search_type=&amp;amp;aq=f">here&lt;/a>. Â I
 managed to escape without a sunburn thanks to liberal application of SPF 50 sunscreen and a hat, but the
 allergies were another story. Â Apparently, Austin is unofficially the &lt;a
 href="http://www.barrypopik.com/index.php/new_york_city/entry/allergy_capital_of_the_world_austin_nickname/">allergy
 capital of the world&lt;/a>. Â It hit me so hard I was sneezing constantly and wishing Tylenol made a "snot
 buckets" formula. Â But I had a blast. Â I can't wait to find out who will be there next year.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>Other concerts I've been to recently include &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/ryanadams">Ryan Adams &amp;amp; The
 Cardinals&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/thetingtings">The Ting Tings&lt;/a>, and &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/weezer">Weezer&lt;/a>. Â The Ryan Adams show was at Verizon Wireless Theater. Â It
 was my third time to see him and he's one of those artists who sounds even better live. Â They played a lot of
 songs from their new album. Â I saw The Ting Tings at the new Houston House of Blues. Â I was not impressed with
 the place as a restaurant nor as a concert venue, but the band put on a good show. Â My only criticism would be
 that the amount of effort the two band members put into constantly jumping between instruments and grabbing them
 from roadies at just the right point in the song detracted from their performance a bit. Â Would it be THAT bad
 to add an extra member for touring? Â The Weezer show was at Reliant Arena. Â It was my second time to see them
 live. Â Highlights include a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3UfzjY0fHBI">note-for-note perfect
 performance of Pink Floyd's "Time"&lt;/a> and about 30 local amateur musicians playing a variety of instruments
 (guitars, flutes, saxaphones, trumpets, tubas, hand drums, etc.) with Weezer themselves just singing for a few
 songs (here's &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vFBd97rDXyA">Island in the Sun&lt;/a>). Â Even funnier was
 Rivers pointing to a couple people to play the solos in the songs.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>I'm going to see &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/ofmontreal">Of Montreal&lt;/a>Â on Tuesday night. Â They were
 amazing when I saw them the first time last year, so it should be another good show. Â Their new album is a bit
 schizophrenic, but who really wants to listen to a band who becomes formulaic and fails to evolve? Â Speaking of
 new music, I grabbed the &lt;a href="http://www.pitchforkmedia.com/node/147226">new Ryan Adams on vinyl&lt;/a>
 (complete with a bonus 7" and alternate cover art) last night. Â And I can't get &lt;a
 href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=97WPxtEtTEU">Matt &amp;amp; Kim's new song "Daylight"&lt;/a> out of my head.
 Â It's perfect to crank up while driving around with the windows down and sunroof open this time of year.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>The guys from &lt;a href="http://guestroom-records.com/">Guest Room Records&lt;/a> in Oklahoma City/Norman have a
 podcast called "&lt;a href="http://shoesareforwork.libsyn.com/">Shoes Are for Work&lt;/a>". Â They play about 10 indie
 rock songs in each episode and discuss new releases. Â I highly recommend it if you're a music freak like I am.
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>And now, the running update. Â My marathon training has been going well since I picked up some &lt;a
 href="http://www.slstri.com/catalog/item/6600182/6463940.htm">SLS Compression Sox&lt;/a> (AKA dork socks) a
 little over a month ago. Â My calves/feet are a lot less sore after running with them and they make longer runs
 much easier. Â Props to Brett for mentioning these on his &lt;a href="http://www.zentriathlon.com/blog/">Zen &amp;amp;
 The Art of Triathlon&lt;/a> podcast. Â I've also taken his suggestion of doing 10 pushups for every mile on my
 shorter runs. Â Running six miles and doing 60 pushups in less than an hour is manly. Â I dare you to say
 otherwise.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>I did a 20 mile run a couple weekends ago in about 3:30 and burned 3919 calories (that's more than a pound!)
 along the way:&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SRXpbH5qhOI/AAAAAAAAADo/NFwKi09sfVU/s1600-h/DSCF0384.JPG">&lt;img
 style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 240px;"
 src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SRXpbH5qhOI/AAAAAAAAADo/NFwKi09sfVU/s320/DSCF0384.JPG"
 border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5266371991466312930" />&lt;/a>&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>That was a semi-relaxed pace, so hopefully I can finish the &lt;a href="http://www.rnrsa.com/home.html">San
 Antonio Rock N Roll Marathon&lt;/a> next weekend in 4:15-4:30. Â Since this will be my first marathon, I'm
 trying not to be too concerned about the time.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>I guess that's enough for this variety pack of the life and times of Andy. Â Maybe I should post more often so
 each entry can have a topic and a meaningful title. Â Hmmm...something to consider...&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Ohhhhhhklahoma! Where the wind comes sweepin' down the plain...</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/09/18/ohhhhhhklahoma-where-the-wind-comes-sweepin-down-the-plain.../</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/09/18/ohhhhhhklahoma-where-the-wind-comes-sweepin-down-the-plain.../</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 I hightailed it out of Houston last Wednesday when it was pretty clear Ike was gonna slap us around. Â Unlike most of
 those trying to evacuate, I eschewed the ever popular I-10 and I-45 routes for Highway 6. Â I followed that up
 through Waco and then hit I-35 up to my parents' in Oklahoma City. Â Along the way, I enjoyed another non-Dominican
 cigar and cranked the tunes.&lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>Since I've been in OKC, I've made the most of it. Â Power was out in our office, so I didn't do any work until
 Tuesday. Â I hit &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/guestroomrecords">Guest Room Records&lt;/a> on the north side of
 town where I picked up the Black Kids' "&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Partie-Traumatic-Black-Kids/dp/B001AZI1XC/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1221789840&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Partie
 Traumatic&lt;/a>", Hot Hot Heat's "&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Make-Up-Breakdown-Hot-Heat/dp/B00006L3PY/ref=pd_bbs_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1221788588&amp;amp;sr=8-3">Make
 Up the Breakdown&lt;/a>", Ryan Adams' "&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Follow-Lights-Ryan-Adams-Cardinals/dp/B000VZC4DK/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1221789870&amp;amp;sr=1-1">Follow
 the Lights&lt;/a>" EP, The Cure's "&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Staring-At-Sea-Singles-Cure/dp/B00002615M/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1221789896&amp;amp;sr=1-2">Staring
 at the Sea&lt;/a>", and Pink Floyd's "&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Wall-Pink-Floyd/dp/B0000025H6/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1221789932&amp;amp;sr=1-3">The
 Wall&lt;/a>" on vinyl. Â While I love my Cactus, Guest Room is a helluva store. Â They also have a store in
 Norman, home of my alma mater, &lt;a href="http://www.ou.edu/web/home.html">OU&lt;/a> (Boomer Sooner!), which I plan
 to visit on my way out of town.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>I've done a lot hanging out with friends. Â We went to &lt;a
 href="http://oklahomacity.citysearch.com/profile/33547844/oklahoma_city_ok/electro_lounge.html">Electro
 Lounge&lt;/a> one night and I was thoroughly impressed. Â Great beer selection (&lt;a
 href="http://www.sierranevada.com/">Sierra Nevada&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.stonebrew.com/">Stone&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.unibroue.com/english.cfm">Unibroue&lt;/a>, etc.) and an amazing jukebox (&lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/tokyopoliceclub">Tokyo Police Club&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/silversunpickups">Silversun Pickups&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/peterbjornandjohn">Peter Bjorn and John&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/pixies">The Pixies&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/flaminglips">Flaming
 Lips&lt;/a>, and on and on). Â My kind of place! Â We hit &lt;a href="http://www.makersokc.com/">Maker's&lt;/a> in &lt;a
 href="http://www.bricktownokc.com/">Bricktown&lt;/a>Â another night for cigars and cocktails. Â I saw theÂ &lt;a
 href="http://www.pitchforkmedia.com/article/news/40060-its-official-flaming-lips-alley-oklahoma-city">Flaming
 Lips Alley&lt;/a> street sign for the first time there but unfortunately I wasn't able to get a good picture of
 it with my phone.&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>Last night, we watched some friends' band play happy hour at &lt;a
 href="http://www.mickeymantlesteakhouse.com/">Mickey Mantle's&lt;/a> downtown. Â After that, we ended up at &lt;a
 href="http://www.buffalowildwings.com/">Buffalo Wild Wings&lt;/a> for karaoke. Â It's been quite awhile since I
 did it, but I rose above the mediocrity of many of my fellow karaokers (okay, so that may not really be a word)
 to deliver an animated performance of John Michael Montgomery's "Sold (The Grundy County Auction Incident)".
 Â &lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>&lt;br />&lt;/div>
 &lt;div>I'm so ready to head back to H-Town, but dreading the stench in my fridge. Â I still have no power, but luckily
 Jamie snagged us a place where we can stay for a couple weeks if necessary. Â &lt;a
 href="http://www.sing365.com/music/lyric.nsf/Houston-lyrics-/DAA194A3BE41F9EA48256E1D001543AA">As Bobby Bare
 said&lt;/a>, I'm "going back to Houston Houston Houston".&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>My Epic 17 Mile Run &amp; Other Moderately Fascinating Stuff</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/20/my-epic-17-mile-run-other-moderately-fascinating-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/20/my-epic-17-mile-run-other-moderately-fascinating-stuff/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 I haven't blogged for about three weeks! While I have the occasional reader, I don't think anyone's had to deal with
 a huge hole in their lives as a result of my absence. I could blame it on the heat or the fact that we're now more
 than halfway through the year and I've taken a total of one day of vacation so far. But I guess I don't have any
 real reason other than I just didn't feel like it. So what have I been up to? Mainly, I've been doing the work
 thing, going to concerts, trying to stay on my marathon training plan, and hanging out with Jamie. (Incidentally,
 the optional comma before the "and" is known an &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxford_comma">oxford comma&lt;/a>
 and is also the name of a bad ass &lt;a href="http://youtube.com/watch?v=P_i1xk07o4g">Vampire Weekend
 song&lt;/a>...)&lt;br />&lt;br />I guess I'll start with the concerts. I saw &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/harryandthepotters">Harry and the Potters&lt;/a> @ Walter's on July 8. If you're a fan
 of the Harry Potter books and haven't heard of this band, check them out! All of their songs are (loosely) based on
 the books and they are hilarious! Here's a video I took of "The Weasel". That's a guy in a squid costume jumping on
 stage to play the drums:&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;object height="344" width="425">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/nNOpIWn6iFI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/nNOpIWn6iFI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1"
 type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" height="344"
 width="425">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;br />&lt;br />This past Friday, we saw &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/officialtillyandthewall">Tilly and the Wall&lt;/a> play at the &lt;a
 href="http://www.engineroomlive.com/">Engine Room&lt;/a>. Jamie is a big fan and while I've heard a few of their
 albums, I really like their latest, "&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/o-Tilly-Wall/dp/B0017V7HCK/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1216593115&amp;amp;sr=8-1">O&lt;/a>".
 Before this album, their percussion consisted of a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tap_dancing">tap
 dancer&lt;/a>. Yep, the only indie rock band I know of that has a tap dancer. With "O", they added a drummer to
 reinforce the tap dancing. Here's the song they opened with, "Too Excited":&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;object height="344"
 width="425">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/Fli6mWNuceY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/Fli6mWNuceY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1"
 type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" height="344"
 width="425">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;br />&lt;br />A local band called &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/thewildmoccasins">Wild Moccasins&lt;/a> opened for Tilly. Like the Young Mammals, this
 band is another set of whippersnappers with buckets of talent. Who knew Houston had music of this caliber? I thought
 all we had given to the music world was &lt;a
 href="http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=sizzurp">sizzurp&lt;/a>, &lt;a
 href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grill_%28jewelry%29">grills&lt;/a>, and &lt;a
 href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Jones_%28rapper%29">Mike Jones' phone number&lt;/a> ad
 nauseum.&lt;br />&lt;br />My running has been going well. A couple weeks ago, Jamie and I set out midday for a 14 mile run
 in the Bayou Park/Memorial Park area. The heat was almost unbearable, but I did manage to finish. Jamie, being a bit
 more sane, cut her run short and logged eight miles. We decided that we would start our long run early this morning,
 so we set out around 6:45 am. We ran from my place to Terry Hershey park and ran through the park for a bit before
 turning around to head back. I did 17 miles in three hours and 13 minutes. Jamie turned around at mile seven so she
 did 14 miles. Overall, I felt pretty good, especially considering that I burned 3500 calories (that's a pound!)
 along the way. After the run, I ate the first of many post-run meals and took a well deserved nap. And now, I'm
 heading to the fridge for some well deserved beer...&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>STP Concert Videos</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/01/stp-concert-videos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/01/stp-concert-videos/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 The Stone Temple Pilots concert this past Saturday &lt;strong>ROCKED&lt;/strong>! See &lt;a
 href="http://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=dammitandy+stone+temple+pilots&amp;amp;search_type=&amp;amp;aq=f">my
 videos on YouTube&lt;/a> for proof, you skeptics. I didn't see them "back in the day" so it was great to finally
 get the chance. Only two things could have made it better - new songs (where are they, guys?) and reasonable prices
 for beer (they were $10 for a 24 oz Shiner). But as I said before, I'm not much of a ranter so I'll leave it at
 that.&lt;br />&lt;br />Here's "Dead and Bloated", one of the most rockinest (that's my "Aww yeah!" a few seconds into the
 song):&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;object height="344" width="425">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/v5JkPgvVkWM&amp;amp;hl=en">
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true">&lt;embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/v5JkPgvVkWM&amp;hl=en"
 type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Vinyl LP Record Is 60 Years Old Today</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/21/vinyl-lp-record-is-60-years-old-today/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/21/vinyl-lp-record-is-60-years-old-today/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 I just got an email from &lt;a href="http://www.soundstagedirect.com/">Sound Stage Direct&lt;/a>, one of my favorite
 online record stores, which said the &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LP_album">vinyl LP record&lt;/a> is 60 years
 old today (invented June 21, 1948 by &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Carl_Goldmark">Peter Goldmark&lt;/a>).
 I searched good ol' YouTube and found the video below which does a good job of providing some history about the
 format as well as some insight into how exactly records are made. Very interesting...&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;object
 height="344" width="425">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/tggLYE87Ed0&amp;amp;hl=en">&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/tggLYE87Ed0&amp;amp;hl=en" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" height="344"
 width="425">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Mates of State Concert &amp; Restaurant Stuff</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/15/mates-of-state-concert-restaurant-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/15/mates-of-state-concert-restaurant-stuff/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Jamie I saw &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/matesofstate">Mates of State&lt;/a> this past Thursday at &lt;a
 href="http://www.warehouselive.com/">Warehouse Live&lt;/a>. I've really been digging their new album, &lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Re-Arrange-Us-Mates-State/dp/B0016MJ2PU/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1213562189&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Re-Arrange
 Us&lt;/a> and it was my first time to see them live. For only two people, their unique combination of keyboard,
 drums, and vocal harmony makes for a nice, full sound. I picked their latest up on vinyl, which overflowed my record
 collection into its &lt;a href="http://www.ikea.com/us/en/catalog/products/40101276">2nd crate&lt;/a>.&lt;br />&lt;br />Here's a
 video I took of "Get Better" and "Think Long":&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;object height="344" width="425">
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/Xvy7qcLM-PQ&amp;amp;hl=en">&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/Xvy7qcLM-PQ&amp;amp;hl=en" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" height="344"
 width="425">&lt;/embed>&lt;/object>&lt;br />&lt;br />Jamie surprised me with the &lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Fearless-Critic-Houston-Restaurant-Guide/dp/0974014346/">Fearless Critic's guide to
 Houston restaurants&lt;/a> and since I've been wanting some Korean food for awhile now, we checked the reviews and
 decided to try &lt;a
 href="http://houston.citysearch.com/profile/43106853/houston_tx/bonga_korean_restaurant.html">Bonga&lt;/a> the
 other night. I lived in Korea a couple times as a kid when my dad was stationed there, so I was familiar with a few
 of the dishes. We shared &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bulgogi">bulgogi&lt;/a> and &lt;a
 href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kimchi">kimchi&lt;/a>, two of the most well-known. It was great to try something
 new and the review gave us confidence that we wouldn't be disappointed. We weren't. The guide gave it a grade of A-
 and I have to agree. Very tasty stuff at a reasonable price.&lt;br />&lt;br />We met some friends at &lt;a
 href="http://www.onioncreekcafe.com/">Onion Creek&lt;/a> for dinner last night, mainly because I wanted to try &lt;a
 href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/profile/337/43157">Saint Arnold Divine Reserve #6&lt;/a>, a limited release beer
 OC has on draft. This edition is an American &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Barley_wine">Barleywine&lt;/a> and
 for those of you who aren't beer geeks, think of running to the record store when your favorite band puts out a new
 album. Only replace record store with &lt;a href="http://www.specsonline.com/">Spec's&lt;/a> and album with limited
 edition microbrew. In other words, something to get excited about if you're into such things. The beer weighs in at
 a hefty 10% abv, so a couple pints was all I could endure in one sitting.&lt;br />&lt;br />This morning, I wanted some
 non-&lt;a href="http://www.starbucks.com/">corporate coffee&lt;/a>, so I decided to stop by &lt;a
 href="http://www.b4-u-eat.com/houston/restaurants/reviews/rsv0996.asp">Cafe Artiste&lt;/a> for some. I was very
 disappointed to find the parking lot empty and a "For Lease" sign in the window. That was such a great place! It
 will be missed...&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>French Kicks Show, New Records, and a 10 Mile Run</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/08/french-kicks-show-new-records-and-a-10-mile-run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/08/french-kicks-show-new-records-and-a-10-mile-run/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 &lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SEzBNIByanI/AAAAAAAAACc/KgIjTg0sKiw/s1600-h/DSCF0177.JPG">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer;"
 src="http://1.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SEzBNIByanI/AAAAAAAAACc/KgIjTg0sKiw/s320/DSCF0177.JPG" alt=""
 id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5209751300198263410" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />Once again, I packed a lot of fun into the
 weekend. Jamie and I went to the &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/frenchkicks">French Kicks&lt;/a> concert at &lt;a
 href="http://www.4215washington.com/">Walter's&lt;/a> on Friday night with some friends. Houston's own &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/youngmammals">Young Mammals&lt;/a> (formerly The Dimes) opened and made me a fan
 almost instantly. It was my second time to see the French Kicks and they put on a great show yet again.&lt;br />&lt;br />I
 took it easy Saturday. I got a &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Humidor">humidor&lt;/a> for some quality cigars I
 recently procured and then paid another visit to my music mecca, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/cactusmv">Cactus
 Records&lt;/a>. There was a DJ spinning classic blues records at Cactus and &lt;a
 href="http://www.saintarnold.com/">Saint Arnold&lt;/a> once again provided free beer. I sipped a beer as I flipped
 through the new records. I had planned to get the &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/spoon">Spoon&lt;/a> records I needed
 to complete my collection (I already had &lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Ga/dp/B000RGSOQO/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987503&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Ga
 Ga Ga Ga Ga&lt;/a> and &lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Sneaks-US-Bonus-Tracks/dp/B000067FU3/ref=pd_bbs_9?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987503&amp;amp;sr=8-9">Series
 of Sneaks&lt;/a>), but was also excited to find &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/bornruffians">Born Ruffians&lt;/a>'
 latest as well. So my collection now includes:&lt;br />
 &lt;ul>
 &lt;li>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Girls-Can-Tell-Spoon/dp/B000056O2Q/ref=pd_bbs_sr_5?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987503&amp;amp;sr=8-5">Spoon
 - Girls Can Tell&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Kill-Moonlight-Spoon/dp/B000069DOH/ref=pd_bbs_sr_4?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987503&amp;amp;sr=8-4">Spoon
 - Kill The Moonlight&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Gimme-Fiction-Spoon/dp/B00082ZRN0/ref=pd_bbs_sr_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987503&amp;amp;sr=8-2">Spoon
 - Gimme Fiction&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Red-Yellow-Blue-Born-Ruffians/dp/B00133KEEU/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987675&amp;amp;sr=8-1">Born
 Ruffians - Red Yellow &amp;amp; Blue&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ul>So other than the hard to find &lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Telephono-Soft-Effects-Spoon/dp/B000FUF870/ref=pd_bbs_10?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1212987503&amp;amp;sr=8-10">Telephono
 &amp;amp; Soft Effects&lt;/a>, my Spoon vinyl collection is now complete.&lt;br />&lt;br />I finished the weekend off with a
 10 mile run at Terry Hershey park. It was my first time to run there and the rolling hills were a nice change from
 the flats I usually run. I averaged about 10:30/mile, which is a little slower than I'd like but I took one minute
 walk breaks every eight minutes to avoid wearing myself out. I finished up with 2100 calories burned, which I
 promptly started replacing with a &lt;a href="http://www.chipotle.com/">Chipotle&lt;/a> burrito and some &lt;a
 href="http://www.saintarnold.com/beers/amber.html">Saint Arnold Amber&lt;/a>. I'm beat but feeling pretty
 accomplished. Off to bed to now to sleep like a baby...
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Shampoo for My Shaved Head &amp; A Lesson in the Metric System</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/05/shampoo-for-my-shaved-head-a-lesson-in-the-metric-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/05/shampoo-for-my-shaved-head-a-lesson-in-the-metric-system/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Today I stopped by my local Sport Clips to get some more shampoo. Yes, even shaved heads need to be washed with
 quality shampoo. Trust me, it's that much more important when people can see every inch of your scalp. I go with the
 &lt;a href="http://www.paulmitchell.com/Products/TeaTree/Care/Pages/TeaTreeSpecialShampoo.aspx">Paul Mitchell Tea Tree
 stuff&lt;/a>. At first, I liked it for the tingly sensation, but I guess my head is way too cool for that now
 because I don't feel a thing when I use it. But my hair always looks great (ha ha ha, I know) so I continue using
 it.&lt;br />&lt;br />As I perused the shampoo selection and various sizes, I noticed a 1L mega size alongside my usual
 500ml size. Since there were no prices on them, I asked the girl behind the counter what the price difference was
 between the two sizes. She told me, and even though the larger size contained twice as much as the other size, the
 price was a little less than double. I said something along those lines more to myself than to her and she said,
 "No, it's three times the shampoo." I was a bit confused by her statement because I learned the metric system in
 elementary school and 1L = 1000ml = 2 x 500ml. I pointed this out and she said, "Hmm, I learn something new every
 day." To downplay my intellectual superiority and to make her feel better for not knowing, I said, "Well, if you
 tell people it's three times as much, maybe you'll sell more." Now I wonder to myself whether she'll do just that or
 try to impress people with her newfound knowledge of the metric system...&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>The Flying Tomato</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/02/the-flying-tomato/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/02/the-flying-tomato/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 &lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SEQN-XVozdI/AAAAAAAAACU/XwQJUNJAscM/s1600-h/080414_park_3084_Fitlow.jpg">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;"
 src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SEQN-XVozdI/AAAAAAAAACU/XwQJUNJAscM/s320/080414_park_3084_Fitlow.jpg"
 alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5207302434214956498" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />Yes, it's been over a week yet again
 since my last post. If I actually had some readers, this would be a bad thing. But since I don't, I guess it doesn't
 really matter much. If anyone does read this drivel, please leave a comment so I can feel good about myself.
 Actually, I don't need anyone to make me feel good about myself, but it would be nice to know you're reading
 this.&lt;br />&lt;br />I, like hundreds of other people yesterday ventured out to Bayou Park for the grand opening of the
 &lt;a href="http://www.houstontx.gov/parks/lee-joepark.html">Lee and Joe Jamail Skate Park&lt;/a>. For those of you who
 haven't been following its construction, this is a FREE public skate park just outside of downtown. I dabbled in
 skateboarding back in 6th &amp;amp; 7th grade and still hop on my board from time to time to ride back and forth like
 I'm cool. I really feel like the old guy at the skate park, but the kids don't seem to mind and I try to stay out of
 their way. I didn't skate yesterday, and instead joined the crowd around the side of the "expert" bowl. We were
 treated to demos by some of the top pro skaters, most of whom I didn't recognize since I followed the sport much
 more closely "back in the day". But none other than &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaun_White">Shaun White
 (Olympic gold medal snowboarder, aka The Flying Tomato)&lt;/a> was there only on a skateboard. I felt very
 privileged to see him in action. Awesome!&lt;br />&lt;br />In other news, Jamie and I saw the Old 97's at Meridian on
 Friday. They played a bunch of songs from their new album. There was even a wedding proposal on stage during the
 sugary sweet "Question". I'm liking their new album more and more each time I listen to it.&lt;br />&lt;br />I also saw
 the new &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0367882/">Indiana Jones movie&lt;/a> over the weekend. It fit nicely with
 the others and seemed to prepare Shia LaBeouf to take on the role of Indy in the next movie. I guess we'll see. My
 only beef with the movie was the odd ending, but it is George Lucas, after all.&lt;br />&lt;br />I finally managed to try
 some of &lt;a href="http://www.southernstarbrewery.com/">Southern Star Brewing'&lt;/a>s beer at &lt;a
 href="http://www.beerknurd.com/">The Flying Saucer&lt;/a> over the weekend. Southern Star is a new brewery up near
 Conroe that was started by a guy I know from my homebrew club and one of his friends. I tried their &lt;a
 href="http://www.southernstarbrewery.com/SSBBeers.asp">Pine Belt Pale Ale&lt;/a> and really liked it. Hop nectar,
 for sure. Good luck, guys!&lt;br />&lt;br />Back to work...&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on 30</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/07/thoughts-on-30/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/07/thoughts-on-30/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 As I'm staring down 30 (tomorrow at 7:01 pm Central to be exact) I should probably blog about how awful it is, but
 now that it's inevitable, I really don't think it's all that scary. I pretty much act like I'm six as often as I
 can. I've worn one of my favorite t-shirts, a He-Man ringer, for years. I just recently picked up a 'Vote Optimus
 08' Transformers t-shirt, too. Yep, still very much a kid. But along the way, I have learned a few
 things.&lt;br />&lt;br />The meaning of life? Enjoy it. That's all. If there's something in your life keeping you from
 doing that, get rid of it. Whether it's a job you dread or people you despise, do what you can to change the
 situation. An obvious exception is family. All you can do is try to get along with them.&lt;br />&lt;br />Keeping up with
 the Joneses? An utter waste of time. If your existence is so hollow that you think material possessions are a
 substitute for living, figure out who you are and quit comparing yourself to others.&lt;br />&lt;br />Music can heal all
 wounds. It's a cure-all for any bad mood and the perfect complement to any good one.&lt;br />&lt;br />What other people
 think about you is irrelevant. Be yourself regardless of what others think. True happiness comes from being
 surrounded by people who like you for who you are, not for living up to some ideal the shallow people try to hold
 you to.&lt;br />&lt;br />I'll add to this as I think of things, but I'd better get to bed. I need to rest up for what will
 most likely be a late night of celebrating. Jamie &amp;amp; I are meeting some friends for dinner and drinks. And I'm
 planning on taking Friday off so I won't be holding anything back.&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Camping @ Pace Bend &amp; A New Personal Record For Downhill Speed!</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/04/camping-@-pace-bend-a-new-personal-record-for-downhill-speed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/04/camping-@-pace-bend-a-new-personal-record-for-downhill-speed/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 &lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SB49RTrWruI/AAAAAAAAACM/qhgELlXAhJY/s1600-h/DSCF0134.JPG">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0pt 10px 10px 0pt; float: left; cursor: pointer;"
 src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SB49RTrWruI/AAAAAAAAACM/qhgELlXAhJY/s320/DSCF0134.JPG" alt=""
 id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5196658387581316834" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />I had a great time camping this weekend
 with some friends at &lt;a
 href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=pace+bend+park+austin,+tx&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;ll=30.445936,-98.037786&amp;amp;spn=0.040401,0.09407&amp;amp;z=14&amp;amp;iwloc=B">Pace
 Bend Park&lt;/a> next to Lake Travis, TX. For the most part, we just hung out enjoying tasty beer (&lt;a
 href="http://www.saintarnold.com/">Saint Arnold&lt;/a>'s Lawnmower/Summer Pilsner/Amber and &lt;a
 href="http://www.sierranevada.com/index2.asp">Sierra Nevada&lt;/a> Pale Ale for you connoisseurs), a fine &lt;a
 href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cohiba_%28cigar_brand%29">Cuban cigar&lt;/a>, and the perfect weather. One of
 the highlights of the trip for me was setting a new personal record for downhill speed on our 35 mile bike ride
 around the lake. Before that ride, my max downhill speed was somewhere between 40-45 mph. Yesterday, I topped out at
 51.2 mph (can I get a "Hell yeah!"?) going down the biggest hill of the ride. I was literally shaking at the bottom
 of the hill from the rush. What a thrill! This one downhill made up for all the grueling climbs and the slight
 sunburn from the rest of the ride. I've included a picture of my bike computer as proof.&lt;br />&lt;br />I'd say the only
 downside of the trip was the inconsiderate jackasses who insisted on blaring their music in the wee hours of the
 night both Friday and Saturday. Why do these people always listen to the crappiest music? We heard a mind-numbing
 mix of horrid techno and the most cliched 80's rock ballads at ridiculous volumes. I'd much prefer to go to sleep to
 the sounds of nature.&lt;br />&lt;br />Today on the way out of Austin, we stopped for brunch at &lt;a
 href="http://www.cafemagnolia.com/">Magnolia Cafe&lt;/a>. It was my first time to eat there and it's now another
 place on my growing list of great restaurants to visit when in our state's capital city.&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Up at 6:00 am on a Saturday...</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/19/up-at-600-am-on-a-saturday.../</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/19/up-at-600-am-on-a-saturday.../</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 So I'm up at 6:00 am on a Saturday morning about to go meet some friends for a bike ride. We'll be doing at least 25
 miles, but maybe 50 if we feel up for it. Crazy I know, but there's a certain excitement around getting up early,
 eating a carbolicious breakfast, drinking some coffee, and hitting the road for awhile. My only real complaint is
 how much gear is involved in a simple bike ride. For those of you who have read Aldous Huxley's "Brave New World"
 (if not, I highly recommend it), cycling is like one of those sports mentioned in the book that requires an arsenal
 of equipment to participate. A short list of things I've assembled for this morning's ride include: cycling
 jersey/shorts/shoes, heart rate monitor, helmet, gloves, sunglasses, spare bike tubes/CO2 cartridges, energy bars,
 energy gels, Gatorade, water, recovery drink. Insane, huh?</description></item><item><title>Son Volt with Bobby Bare Jr. @ The Continental Club, Negativland @ Rice's Aurora Picture Show</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/18/son-volt-with-bobby-bare-jr.-@-the-continental-club-negativland-@-rices-aurora-picture-show/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/18/son-volt-with-bobby-bare-jr.-@-the-continental-club-negativland-@-rices-aurora-picture-show/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 &lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SAi3QTUSi6I/AAAAAAAAABU/cHmJYTb78EE/s1600-h/IMG00069.jpg">&lt;img
 style="margin: 0pt 0pt 10px 10px; float: right; cursor: pointer;"
 src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SAi3QTUSi6I/AAAAAAAAABU/cHmJYTb78EE/s320/IMG00069.jpg" alt=""
 id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5190600061235661730" border="0" />&lt;/a>&lt;br />I caught a couple of great shows the past
 two days. Wednesday night, I went to see &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/sonvolt">Son Volt&lt;/a> at The Continental
 Club. For those who are not familiar with the band, Jay Farrar the lead singer/song writer, was previously in Uncle
 Tupelo (forefathers of the "No Depression"/alt-country genre) and one of my favorite bands - &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/wilco">Wilco&lt;/a>. There was a bit of a falling out between him and Jeff Tweedy
 during the recording of the epic "Yankee Hotel Foxtrot" album and Son Volt was born. Son Volt put on a great show.
 Their lead guitar player was a virtuoso, playing flawlessly with perfect tone.&lt;br />&lt;br />&lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/bobbybarejr">Bobby Bare Jr&lt;/a> opened. I hadn't heard of him previously but really
 liked his songs. The bass player was hilarious. He had on a "Daniel-san" like headband and danced around like he was
 playing butt rock rather than sensitive alt-country. He cracked me up when he asked for "more mustache" in the
 monitors!&lt;br />&lt;br />Last night, I had the pleasure of experiencing &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/officialnegativland">Negativland&lt;/a> at &lt;a
 href="http://www.aurorapictureshow.org/">Rice's Aurora Picture Show&lt;/a> after a friend invited me to check it
 out. The show can best be described as a fictional radio show examining religion. The show was titled "It's All In
 Your Head" and posits that religion, like everything else, is man made. By design, it is intended to make listeners
 question their beliefs and compare/contrast them with other religions. To enhance the listening experience, the
 audience was given a colorful piÃ±ata blindfold and invited to wear it throughout the show. I took their suggestion
 and zoned out a bit as I soaked up the chaotic sound collage they created live on stage. One of the members of the
 group said no computers were used to produce the show, just an array of electronics equipment including samplers,
 turntables, and other "complicated devices". This was very different than anything I'd ever been to but I thoroughly
 enjoyed it.&lt;br />&lt;br />Before the show, we wandered around the Rice campus a bit until we found &lt;a
 href="http://valhalla.rice.edu/">Valhalla&lt;/a>, an on-campus bar run by grad students. The beer was ridiculously
 cheap. I drank St. Arnold Bock for $1.15 a glass. I'll always love the Gingerman, but I may have found another
 option when in that area. The campus was beautiful. I'd never been there, but walking around made me want to go back
 to school again. Maybe someday soon. The whole studying thing doesn't appeal to me at the moment.&lt;br />&lt;br />I'm
 supposed to be working now, so I'd better wrap this up. I've included a picture I took in a friend of a friend's
 apartment building. I think it speaks for itself.&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>All the cool kids are doing it</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/15/all-the-cool-kids-are-doing-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/04/15/all-the-cool-kids-are-doing-it/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'>
 Here goes my foray into proper blogging. I decided to do this for several reasons.&lt;br />
 &lt;ol>
 &lt;li>I used to enjoy writing until years of composing corporate email took their toll on my once sharp literary
 wit.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>Sometimes I think I live in my head too much. I could probably benefit from attempting to organize my
 thoughts in a coherent manner on a regular basis.&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>It seems like a good way to let people know what's going on in my life without running the risk of repeating
 the same story to the same people over and over. Those of you who decide this is worth reading will be
 treated to much more efficient conversation (if efficient conversation is your thing).&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>"Blog" sounds so much cooler than "journal" or "diary".&lt;/li>
 &lt;li>All the cool kids are doing it.&lt;br />&lt;/li>
 &lt;/ol>&lt;br />I guess this will do for a first entry. Send me comments, links to your blogs, whatever...&lt;br />&lt;/span>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>