<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Berlin on Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/categories/berlin/</link><description>Recent content in Berlin on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 12:45:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/categories/berlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Things I've Learned Since Moving to Berlin</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 12:45:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/east_side_gallery_sunset.jpg" alt="East Side Gallery Sunset" style="margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; display: block" />
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve lived in Berlin for a bit more than six months now. Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It is possible to survive a summer without air conditioning. It&amp;rsquo;s also possible to go all summer without a mosquito bite.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t miss having a car. Public transit is great here so I typically only need one to haul things like furniture. And I can rent one on demand pretty easily with apps like &lt;a href="https://www.drive-now.com/de/en">DriveNow&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I really enjoy bicycling to work, but don&amp;rsquo;t ride for fun as much.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can take beer almost anywhere. The only downside is you&amp;rsquo;re supposed to take the bottles back. It&amp;rsquo;s an endless cycle. They&amp;rsquo;re worth €0.08 each and it&amp;rsquo;s not cool to throw them away in your building&amp;rsquo;s bins.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You need less stuff than you think. No, even less than that. There were a lot of things we moved but didn&amp;rsquo;t use or have room for. This same philosophy applies to daily life in Berlin. Not having a car means carrying what you need with you. &amp;ldquo;Do I really need this jacket?&amp;rdquo; is a good question to ask yourself if it&amp;rsquo;s going to warm up later in the day. At first, I carried a backpack with my laptop, etc. to/from work on the bike, but leaving things in a locker at work proved to be a liberating alternative.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You can order cocktail supplies from Amazon. You can also get them at the grocery store or even at a späti if you are willing to pay a bit more for the convenience.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The paperwork thing is for real. Without fail, I am always in the middle of some bureaucratic battle involving paperwork, waiting, mailing more paperwork, and waiting some more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I thought the cluster of buildings Google Maps showed as the Bürgeramt were abandoned based on &lt;a href="https://igx.4sqi.net/img/general/width960/lO8a2iJHE8snO4Du7k9Ok4isx-N3rYfnvTwq-wkQF0M.jpg">the plant life&lt;/a>. I turns out that they just don&amp;rsquo;t mow/trim things very often. Efficiency?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Every so often, someone on public transit will surprise you with &lt;a href="https://www.thelocal.de/20151211/19-weird-things-you-can-do-on-the-berlin-tube">something crazy&lt;/a> after you thought you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it all.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Things they don&amp;rsquo;t have here: garbage disposals (you dispose or organic waste in a dedicated bin), right turn on red (more about this below), stop signs at every intersection (the rightmost person goes first if there are multiple vehicles), overly attentive waiters.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Obey the traffic signals. There&amp;rsquo;s a reason most Germans wait patiently for traffic signals even when there is no opposing traffic coming. The Polizei will eventually get you if you don&amp;rsquo;t. I stopped before going right on red while biking and some police on bikes came out of nowhere to cut me off and stop me. I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure from my still fledgling German skills, but I think I have a ticket coming in the mail for that soon.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You don&amp;rsquo;t need German very often until you need it. Older people often speak less English and some government officials seem to stick to it even when they know you&amp;rsquo;re struggling. I&amp;rsquo;ve gradually gotten less embarrassed about trying, but I still mess up daily. It&amp;rsquo;s humbling but rewarding as I slowly progress.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Before moving here I knew Berlin had techno on an endless loop in clubs every weekend. But I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that some clubs occasionally have daytime parties, which means I can spend a couple hours there during my son&amp;rsquo;s nap. #dadlife&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People get really excited about seasonal produce here. And for good reason, it&amp;rsquo;s delicious! You will know what&amp;rsquo;s in season by suddenly seeing it EVERYWHERE. &lt;a href="https://www.rnz.de/cms_media/module_img/297/148685_1_org_14910200C55C0C85.jpg">Asparagus&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="http://foodieinberlin.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/07/l1040042.jpg">strawberries&lt;/a>, and chanterelle mushrooms have been some of my favorites so far.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In the US, we call the sport &amp;ldquo;soccer&amp;rdquo; and table game &amp;ldquo;foosball&amp;rdquo;. In Germany, they call the sport &amp;ldquo;fußball&amp;rdquo; (fussball) and the table game &amp;ldquo;kicker&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Skinny(ier) jeans are functional as well as fashionable. For example, looking cool while not getting your jeans caught in your bike chain.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>People either stare at you or don&amp;rsquo;t notice you at all. Either way, you can be yourself without caring what anyone else thinks. Someone is always weirder than you.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I love this city even more than I thought I would. I remind myself every day how fortunate I am to live here.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Aufwiedersehen, Houston! Hallo, Berlin!</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 13:06:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Anyone who has talked to me for more than 10 minutes has probably heard me mention my love for Berlin. I first visited the city about six years ago and almost immediately resolved to make it my home one day. I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to finally announce that &lt;a href="https://media.giphy.com/media/rl0FOxdz7CcxO/giphy.gif">it&amp;rsquo;s happening&lt;/a>! I&amp;rsquo;ll be joining &lt;a href="https://tech.zalando.com/">Zalando&lt;/a> in Berlin next month to do &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.zalando.mobile&amp;amp;hl=en">Android&lt;/a> and hopefully step up my fashion game a bit. &lt;a href="http://www.redherring.com/features/radical-agility-zalando-tech-become-berlins-hottest-engineering-ticket/">Radical Agility&lt;/a> sounds like engineering nirvana to me! After working remotely for the past year and a half, I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being in an office again, especially one where I&amp;rsquo;ll get to work with smart people from all over the world.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>