<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/categories/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:24:19 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Top Albums of 2024</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2024/12/21/top-albums-of-2024/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 10:24:19 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2024/12/21/top-albums-of-2024/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the time of the year when &lt;a href="https://adventofcode.com"&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt; has gotten too elfing hard and I use what&amp;rsquo;s left of the year&amp;rsquo;s productive energy to publish my list of favorite albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered a few new artists/groups this year, but an AI trained only on previous years&amp;rsquo; lists could have correctly guessed half of these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ty Segall - Three Bells&lt;/strong&gt; Another batch of perfectly baked psych pop/rock from a longtime favorite. I saw him play yet again at the Gothic Theatre back in May.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2023</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2023/12/22/top-albums-of-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 17:17:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2023/12/22/top-albums-of-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;d think I&amp;rsquo;d do more with a prestigious domain name like &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org"&gt;andydyer.org&lt;/a&gt; than post a list of my favorite albums once a year. Someday, perhaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year I included several albums from 2022. I listened to them so many times that it felt weird to exclude them solely based on their release date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DoMi &amp;amp; JD Beck - NOT TiGHT (2022)&lt;/strong&gt; Instant favorite. So good! The classic jazz influences are woven throughout. Does that arpeggio sound like something from Coltrane? Giant Steps-like for sure. Did Herbie Hancock inspire that track? Probably, he&amp;rsquo;s playing on it! They combine virtuosity with a nod to the past while sounding entirely unique.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;La Colonie de Vacances - ECHT (2022)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.musicglue.com/la-colonie-de-vacances/about"&gt;Four bands&lt;/a&gt; at the same time! The chaos is surprisingly organized. After listening to it loudly, enough times to get past the initial shock, I came appreciate what they&amp;rsquo;re doing. Undoubtedly, sitting in the middle of these bands in a live setting would be the best way to hear this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Billy Woods &amp;amp; Kenny Segal - Maps&lt;/strong&gt; Rich lyrics anchor this album from the MC who &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Billywoods/comments/o3lplf/re_the_blurred_face/"&gt;values his privacy&lt;/a&gt;. Make sure the Mike&amp;rsquo;s right like Phil Jackson in &amp;lsquo;96.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Czarface - Czarmageddon (2022)/Czartificial Intelligence (2023)&lt;/strong&gt; Comic book rap from Wu-Tang&amp;rsquo;s Inspectah Deck &amp;amp; friends. A perfect skateboard video/pickup basketball game/chill soundtrack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osees - Intercepted Message&lt;/strong&gt; They evolve their sound despite it seeming impossible to continue doing so after all this time. Whether they are covering hold music or evoking the best of Devo, I will dutifully add every one of their albums to my end-of-year lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GOAT - Medicine&lt;/strong&gt; Check out &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RNMuGxuJuv0"&gt;this live set&lt;/a&gt; for a taste of their psych-rock magic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MJ Lenderman - Boat Songs (2022)/And the Wind (Live and Loose, 2023)&lt;/strong&gt; Catchy throwback indie rock from the Wednesday guitar player. I gave this several listens on a Midwestern road trip over the summer. It felt right among the cornfields.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feeble Little Horse - Girl with Fish&lt;/strong&gt; They evoke the fuzzy loud/quiet/loud 90s indie rock sound I love (a perennial theme, I know).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday - Rat Saw God&lt;/strong&gt; - Shoegaze plus a steel guitar and slice of life lyrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nat Myers - Yellow Peril&lt;/strong&gt; To the blues what Charley Crockett is to country, although that&amp;rsquo;s an oversimplification. I was a fan as soon as I heard his voice on top of the guitar. Also successfully road trip/ramblin&amp;rsquo; tested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with a song from each of the above albums:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2022</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2022/12/27/top-albums-of-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 14:43:53 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2022/12/27/top-albums-of-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s top albums list is a mix of chill &amp;amp; aggressive, ranging from folky Americana, to psych rock, and even punk. While past favorites Kendrick Lamar &amp;amp; Earl Sweatshirt both released long-awaited albums, I did not find myself returning to them the way I did with their previous releases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This list is probably the first that has included a new mix of an album that was released in a different year (The Beatles - Revolver), but I think it sounds so modern, its inclusion is defensible. And it&amp;rsquo;s my list, so my rules, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2021</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/12/24/top-albums-of-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 10:09:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/12/24/top-albums-of-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year I said farewell to Berlin, road tripped around southern Germany, and moved to sunny Colorado. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of favorite albums that soundtracked it all:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mdou Moctar - Afrique Victime&lt;/strong&gt; My first concert in over a year and a half, Mdou Moctar did not disappoint. While the guitar playing is undoubtedly the feature, be sure to appreciate the skill of the drummer as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Night Beats - Outlaw RnB&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Night Beats fan &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/"&gt;for years&lt;/a&gt; but until this album, I was convinced I preferred the psych rock of their first couple albums over their more recent soul/R&amp;amp;B sound. This one grew on me more with each listen. They also released a great album of acoustic versions of these tracks and did a Levitation Sessions. I included a track from the latter on the playlist below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuzz - Levitation Sessions&lt;/strong&gt; Just about any Levitation Sessions release makes for a great listen; most definitely this one. There was also a nice &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V9o_P9hKQGk"&gt;Part II of the OSees Levitation Sessions&lt;/a&gt; released this year, but I resisted the urge to include it after having three of their albums on &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/22/top-albums-of-2020/"&gt;last year&amp;rsquo;s list&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fruit Bats - Siamese Dream&lt;/strong&gt; Siamese Dream is one of my all-time favorite albums. This cover album chills everything out and does every track well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buck Meek - Two Saviors&lt;/strong&gt; I surprised myself by how often I kept coming back to the Big Thief guitar player&amp;rsquo;s second solo album. There&amp;rsquo;s so much detail in the lyrics and the melodies are catchy enough to hum to yourself once they infect your subconscious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Floatie - Voyage Out&lt;/strong&gt; Floatie immediately reminded me of Palm, another math-rock favorite of mine. I&amp;rsquo;ve praised their label, &lt;a href="http://www.explodinginsoundrecords.com/"&gt;Exploding in Sound Records&lt;/a&gt;, more than once over the years and Floatie is another good example of the kind of sound I like to have exploding in my vicinity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meatbodies - 333&lt;/strong&gt; Does this sound an awful lot like Fuzz? Yes, and that&amp;rsquo;s precisely why I like it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Na$ty - The Rodez Tapes&lt;/strong&gt; While we patiently await new Kendrick &amp;amp; Earl Sweatshirt albums, Na$ty was a new discovery for me that scratches a similar hip-hop itch. Boasts like &amp;ldquo;So ahead of my time I wrote this rhyme last week&amp;rdquo; flow effortlessly over laid-back lo-fi beats. Dig it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charley Crockett - 10 for Slim &amp;amp; Music City USA&lt;/strong&gt; This year gave us a couple batches of new-but-retro-sounding country songs from Mr. Crockett. I&amp;rsquo;d love to see him live, but tickets are over $100 each! Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll get a copy of each on vinyl and some good whiskey for a night in instead.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday - Twin Plague&lt;/strong&gt; There&amp;rsquo;s always something shoegazey on this list and Wednesday fills that role this year. Droning, swooping, fuzzed out guitars alternating in a loud/quiet dynamic. Yep, this&amp;rsquo;ll do nicely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with a song from each of the above albums:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2020</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/22/top-albums-of-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 12:02:28 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2020/12/22/top-albums-of-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This year was full of unexpected surprises, disappointments, and more for everyone, but music was here to comfort us throughout. Here&amp;rsquo;s my list of favorite albums for the year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hum - Inlet&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone who&amp;rsquo;s talked music with me long enough has heard me express my adoration for Hum. They were the first/one of the first &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/"&gt;bands I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live&lt;/a&gt;. Their particular brand of space rock/shoegaze/whatever-you-want-to-call-it has always been one of my favorites. It&amp;rsquo;s been a long couple decades since their last release, &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=o4VY15Q2_NU"&gt;Downward Is Heavenward&lt;/a&gt;, so I was skeptical whether this year&amp;rsquo;s surprise new album would greet these old ears the same as their earlier releases. It took a few listens for me to warm up to it, but this album is certainly one of my top picks for the year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSees - Protean Threat&lt;/strong&gt; Their name has yet another new spelling and the kraut/prog rock evolution of their sound continues. Longsuffering readers of my top albums lists will recall my love of this band, so no surprise to see them on this year&amp;rsquo;s list again (although I did not include &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; of the albums they released this year). This one works so well as an end-to-end listen that I listened to it a second time in a row on more than one occasion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSees - Levitation Sessions&lt;/strong&gt; Until this year, every summer in Berlin meant an OSees tour stop and a guaranteed great night out. Luckily, the band shared this live recording that serves as a decent surrogate, but you probably won&amp;rsquo;t be showered by thrown beers in your living room.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OSees - Metamorphosed&lt;/strong&gt; Oh, the audacity of including a third album from the same band on a top 10 list! You may not be surprised to learn that there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href="https://thehardtimes.net/music/even-newer-thee-oh-sees-album-somehow-released-new-thee-oh-sees-album/"&gt;Hard Times article&lt;/a&gt; poking fun at the frequency of their album releases. This one is some leftover tracks from last year&amp;rsquo;s Face Stabber double album; a couple short ones and a couple extended jams doing what they do best.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Run the Jewels - RTJ4&lt;/strong&gt; Listening to the hard-hitting lyrics of this album, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget that it was penned before the Black Lives Matter protests erupted earlier this year. That&amp;rsquo;s because systemic racism is nothing new as Mike &amp;amp; El-P so eloquently convey on track after track. Have you ever taken a moment to &amp;ldquo;look at all these slave masters posing on your dollar&amp;rdquo;? It&amp;rsquo;s pretty messed up when you think about it. Meanwhile, &lt;a href="https://99percentinvisible.org/article/fact-follows-fiction-real-bridges-based-euro-banknote-artwork/"&gt;the EU has bridges on their currency&lt;/a&gt; as a symbol of connection, ju$t saying. RTJ also did a live stream of their performance of the entire album. Mike&amp;rsquo;s acapella verse at the end of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FUvoQrcsETg"&gt;Walking in the Snow&lt;/a&gt; is intense!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuzz - III&lt;/strong&gt; While there was no new Ty Segall album this year, the third release from his Fuzz side project gives us a chance to hear him play drums and sing. This time there&amp;rsquo;s a bit of Thin Lizzy-esque guitar harmonies and other new sonic elements to add some color to the Sabbath sludge they so effortlessly conjure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charley Crockett - Welcome to Hard Times&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/zvie5df0SP8?t=65"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do you like sinnin&amp;rsquo;? Well, you will before you go.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; is all the invitation I needed to enter Charley&amp;rsquo;s classic country time machine. The Davy Crockett descendant croons about love and heartbreak while reminding us that the telephone used to play a central role in the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khruangbin - Mordecai&lt;/strong&gt; The Houston trio has continued to explore the funk elements of their sound, which adds some swagger to any walk or cleaning session. I love the quirky adventurousness of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oc50wHexbwg"&gt;Time (You and I) video&lt;/a&gt;. And since &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W9YNkE_JOhA"&gt;Christmas Time Is Here&lt;/a&gt;, check out their version of the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4PzetPqepXA"&gt;Vince Guaraldi song&lt;/a&gt; from A Charlie Brown Christmas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kurt Vile - Speed, Sound, Lonely KV&lt;/strong&gt; After enjoying 2018&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Bottle It In&amp;rdquo; and seeing his show here in Berlin last year, I was happy to see a new EP from Kurt Vile this fall. After several listens, I learned from the &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/163479981/our-show"&gt;All Songs Considered podcast&lt;/a&gt; that there are a couple John Prine songs on it, including a thought-provoking duet with Prine on &amp;ldquo;How Lucky&amp;rdquo;, which recalls a visit to places of our past and what we are lucky enough to remember (or forget). If you are not very familiar with the late great John Prine, the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DZXgZGrVlL4"&gt;original&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kHTmXFfhjz8"&gt;versions&lt;/a&gt; of these two songs are a great place to start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jimi Hendrix - Live in Maui&lt;/strong&gt; As evidenced by numerous other choices on the list, I clearly needed fuzzy guitars and extended jams in high doses this year. I&amp;rsquo;ll end with yet another glimpse into the mastery of Jimi Hendrix. This release covers a pair of concerts the rock legend performed on the side of a dormant volcano in 1970. Watch some of the video to see Jimi make guitar wrangling look easy and timelessly cool. Also, laugh at the tripping hippies waving their hands in front of their far out faces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with a song from each album, but I assure you there are many more you really should hear. Let me know if you find a new favorite or have something else to recommend!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top Albums of 2019</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/23/top-albums-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 17:47:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2019/12/23/top-albums-of-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Time files and it turns out it&amp;rsquo;s been several years since I &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/"&gt;last shared&lt;/a&gt; my favorite albums of the year. Despite the lack of posts, I still keep a list every year and decided it&amp;rsquo;s time once again to highlight some of the albums I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed most:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh Sees - Face Stabber&lt;/strong&gt; Any year that includes an Oh Sees release will find it &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/"&gt;in my top albums list&lt;/a&gt;, so here it is. I also &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/"&gt;see them anytime their tour comes through town&lt;/a&gt;. Again, no exception this year. The band continues its exploration of prog rock while still retaining just enough of their psych rock foundation to sound unmistakably like themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chris Staples - Holy Moly&lt;/strong&gt; Not to be confused with the much more country-fied &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4zAThXFOy2c"&gt;Chris Stapleton&lt;/a&gt;, Chris Staples is a new discovery for me this year. I&amp;rsquo;d describe him as indie singer/songwriter with a strong Wilco sensibility. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing him here in Berlin next month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ty Segall - Deforming Lobes (Live), First Taste&lt;/strong&gt; Similar to the Oh Sees guarantee above, Ty Segall &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/"&gt;always&lt;/a&gt; makes the year&amp;rsquo;s top albums list as well. This year, the prolific psych rocker gave me two albums to love; a live album and the &lt;a href="https://pitchfork.com/reviews/albums/ty-segall-first-taste/"&gt;notably guitarless&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;First Taste&amp;rdquo; (although it&amp;rsquo;s hard to believe some of these sounds aren&amp;rsquo;t guitars).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wilco - Ode to Joy&lt;/strong&gt; Wilco is another perennial favorite of mine. Jeff Tweedy&amp;rsquo;s songwriting is as strong as ever and this album is one that deepens a bit with each listen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Versing - 10000&lt;/strong&gt; A wonderful recreation of that &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2Nsy4h8rD4"&gt;Pavement&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AVtskhcGOtc"&gt;Built to Spill&lt;/a&gt; slacker rock sound with a dash of Nirvana style grunge. All the ingredients for a good album.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoon - Everything Hits at Once (Best Of)&lt;/strong&gt; Spoon is another of my favorites that makes &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/"&gt;any year&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; top albums list. This is a &amp;ldquo;best of&amp;rdquo; spanning most of their albums, with the disappointing absence of a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IVOvxT5GZi8"&gt;killer track&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rCgfLSuf2O8"&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; from &amp;ldquo;Series of Sneaks&amp;rdquo;. Nevertheless, the track order is great and this collection should serve as a solid introduction for anyone as yet unfamiliar with their greatness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Khruangbin - Hasta El Cielo&lt;/strong&gt; Painfully known to me as the band I missed seeing last year due to a calendar time zone mixup, Khruangbin released a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dub_music"&gt;dub&lt;/a&gt; version of their wonderful &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9cN1XCpfWD4"&gt;&amp;ldquo;Con Todo El Mundo&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; album. I love how the different style further mellows what was already a pretty laid back sound. Perfect for a rainy Sunday morning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ari Roar - Best Behavior&lt;/strong&gt; Bouncy guitar and bass lines that remind me of bands like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=59cQWw9ctOA"&gt;Pinback&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VKJkq-fuFKU"&gt;Palm&lt;/a&gt; paired with breezy vocals. Soundtrack a windows-down-stereo-up car ride with this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Sandy) Alex G - House of Sugar&lt;/strong&gt; Introspective and at times haunting lyrics softened with acoustic guitar &amp;amp; a sprinkle of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HcO-NPtj5BI"&gt;lo-fi wooze&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dead Soft - Big Blue&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m a sucker for 90s guitar rock like &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wxlfkFMjLZc"&gt;early Weezer&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sNfocDNZWY8"&gt;Matthew Sweet&lt;/a&gt;. Dead Soft does this well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2015</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late with my annual Top 10 list, but here it is roughly ranked by Google Music play count:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earl Sweatshirt - I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Shit, I Don&amp;rsquo;t Go Outside&lt;/strong&gt; I was finally lucky enough to &lt;a href="http://www.houstonpress.com/music/earl-sweatshirt-revels-in-raps-odd-future-at-warehouse-live-7746980"&gt;see him live&lt;/a&gt; and he didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint. Another great release. This soundtracked numerous skateboard and chill sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vince Staples - Summertime &amp;lsquo;06&lt;/strong&gt; His &amp;ldquo;Hell Can Wait&amp;rdquo; EP made my list last year and I knew this one would be on this year&amp;rsquo;s list right away. The subject matter is heavy, but you may be nodding your head so much at first you won&amp;rsquo;t notice. I recommend multiple listens so you can fully appreciate both its depth and undeniable crunkness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drumcode - A-Sides Volume III&lt;/strong&gt; Ever since getting bitten by the techno bug, I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a solid list of podcasts I listen to regularly like &lt;a href="http://www.droidbehavior.com/blog/podcast/"&gt;Droid Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and Adam Beyer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://drumcode.se/"&gt;Drumcode Radio (DCR)&lt;/a&gt;. This collection of Drumcode singles includes many that were feature on DCR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuzz - II&lt;/strong&gt; This Ty Segall side project returns with another face melting set. For when you want to rock. Hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryan Adams - 1989&lt;/strong&gt; I had successfully avoided knowingly hearing any of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s album until I heard this song-for-song cover album from the prolific Mr. Adams. Now I realize they&amp;rsquo;ve been plaguing my every shopping experience for months. But there&amp;rsquo;s no way around it, these are good songs. I contend they&amp;rsquo;re even better with Ryan Adams performing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panda Bear - Panda Bear Meets the Grim Reaper&lt;/strong&gt; For the uninitiated, Panda Bear is a member of Animal Collective, a pretty kick ass indie psych band. This is his fifth solo album. Reverb, chants, and a masterful combination of Eastern &amp;amp; electronic instruments pay tribute to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lD4sxxoJGkA"&gt;Pet Sounds&lt;/a&gt; and beyond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buxton - Half a Native&lt;/strong&gt; Houston&amp;rsquo;s Buxton delivers an album of honest and heartfelt songs. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, but when Sergio Trevino sings about shyly introducing himself to a woman in &amp;ldquo;Pool Hall&amp;rdquo;, you feel like you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deerhunter - Fading Frontier&lt;/strong&gt; Bradford Cox and crew continue their legacy of jangly rock songs that are hard to categorize, but always sound like Deerhunter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Teens of Style&lt;/strong&gt; I owe this discovery to NPR All Songs Considered&amp;rsquo;s coverage of the CMJ Music Festival. The young Will Toledo&amp;rsquo;s bedroom recordings confirm he has another great album coming when he records in a proper studio in 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wilco - Star Wars&lt;/strong&gt; This Wilco album came out of nowhere&amp;hellip;no press coverage, no teased release date&amp;hellip;just a free download on the interwebz. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s another Wilco album, but one that I enjoyed a bit more than their last two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLiOTTgupZ1CBE0OdDyg1jOfQpwr0VlbA9"&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist&lt;/a&gt; with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2014</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The end of another year means it&amp;rsquo;s time for the annual Top 10 Favorite Albums list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ty Segall - Manipulator&lt;/strong&gt; While not the leader in sheer track plays via my Google Play Music account, this album is perfect all the way through. It certainly spent a lot of time on my turntable as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing - Guilty of Everything&lt;/strong&gt; A wonderful example of the specific brand of rock music I love. Heavily &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zhxXn60Z0yk"&gt;MBV&lt;/a&gt; influenced wall of sound guitars. They were almost deafeningly loud when I saw them at &lt;a href="http://fitzlivemusic.com"&gt;Fitzgerald&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; over the summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whirr - Sway&lt;/strong&gt; One of the members of Nothing also founded Whirr. As you might expect, they have a similar sound. Similarly awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sturgill Simpson - Metamodern Sounds in Country Music&lt;/strong&gt; Like a modern day &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=14ZHn_76QM0"&gt;Waylon Jennings&lt;/a&gt;. While I&amp;rsquo;m not a big country fan, I can appreciate honest, heartfelt songs. These are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoon - They Want My Soul&lt;/strong&gt; Such a consistent band. Their sound evolves slightly with each album, yet they always sound like Spoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meatbodies - Meatbodies&lt;/strong&gt; Ty Segall&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iDEmMyowfPU"&gt;Fuzz&lt;/a&gt; band mate Chad Ubovich also helms Meatbodies. Psych rock, fuzz, reverb, etc. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DuYOMvTLoJo"&gt;Thee Oh Sees&lt;/a&gt;/Ty Segall type rock n&amp;rsquo; roll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parquet Courts - Sunbathing Animal&lt;/strong&gt; Their slacker rock sound reminds me a bit of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lPvhKV3Yg2k"&gt;Pavement&lt;/a&gt;. Simple yet catchy songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheatahs - Cheatahs&lt;/strong&gt; On par with the Nothing and Whirr albums on the list, more fuzzy droning shoegaze-y goodness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schoolboy Q - Oxymoron&lt;/strong&gt; I continued exploring hip-hop this year and this album led the pack. &amp;ldquo;Los Awesome&amp;rdquo; is like a modern day &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uWbXQQG9B6c"&gt;California Love&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_L2vJEb6lVE"&gt;Collard Greens&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; features Kendrick Lamar and name checks Houston. And more. What else do you need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vince Staples - Hell Can Wait&lt;/strong&gt; Vince Staples has &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BGfE-mbdmXg"&gt;collaborated with Earl Sweatshirt&lt;/a&gt; (whose &amp;ldquo;Doris&amp;rdquo; album was on my list last year) and toured this year with Schoolboy Q. Apparently my ear is also finely tuned for a specific style of hip-hop. Whatever the case, this album will get your head nodding if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made a YouTube playlist with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introducing Kollektor</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="why-a-new-app"&gt;Why a new app?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first decided to get into Android development, I created the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary"&gt;Music Library&lt;/a&gt; app to catalog my vinyl collection. It served me well as I learned the ins and outs of Android programming including &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/providers/content-providers.html"&gt;content providers&lt;/a&gt;, interacting with other applications via &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Intent.html"&gt;intents&lt;/a&gt;, working with the file system to save/load images, making API requests, etc. In order to test the workings of the Android app market, I published the ad supported Music Library Free and the paid Music Library versions of the app. In addition to not displaying ads, Music Library also included the ability to backup your collection to the device&amp;rsquo;s SD card and export data to a Google Drive spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Albums of 2013</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Each year, I keep a list of albums that I find myself listening to frequently. This is the time of year when I review the list and pick my top 10. I ventured into hip-hop and electronic music a bit more this year. Psych rock and 90s style fuzz are also well represented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UUc5y1NljXI"&gt;My Bloody Valentine - MBV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YjgEBZhsGJs"&gt;Disclosure - Settle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmpOntxlbcY"&gt;Swearin&amp;rsquo; - Dust in the Gold Sack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eHoKMZf8M0"&gt;Weed - Deserve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLsq8zPvloY"&gt;Thee Oh Sees - Floating Coffin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TPCtrybEt8E"&gt;Night Beats - Sonic Bloom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xfsXK9Lgitk"&gt;Speedy Ortiz - Major Arcana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGEx8SfI540"&gt;Unknown Mortal Orchestra - II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dg0yfie121E"&gt;Waxahatchee - Cerulean Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FCbWLSZrZfw"&gt;Earl Sweatshirt - Doris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Top 10 Albums of 2010</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/12/28/my-top-10-albums-of-2010/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/12/28/my-top-10-albums-of-2010/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'&gt;
 Since I put together my inaugural Top 10 list last year, I may as well make it a tradition. Luckily I had the
 foresight to keep a running list in &lt;a href="http://www.evernote.com/"&gt;Evernote&lt;/a&gt; throughout the year, so the
 tough part was putting them in order. Some may argue about the order of the albums on the list or the exclusion of
 others. I'd love to hear your opinions.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;So without any further &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Eisa5AZ20W0"&gt;jibba jabba&lt;/a&gt;, here's my Top 10
 Albums of 2010 list:&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Gorilla-Manor-Local-Natives/dp/B0032IAB4C/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593217&amp;amp;sr=8-1"&gt;Local
 Natives - Gorilla Manor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The harmonies are amazing. I saw these guys twice this year and
 loved both shows.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Flaming-Stardeath-Dwarfs-Rollins-Peaches/dp/B003D8O8FY/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593246&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Flaming
 Lips - Dark Side of the Moon&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;I was lucky enough to see the Lips perform this on &lt;a
 href="https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/01/02/my-review-of-flaming-lips-new-years-eve/"&gt;NYE 2009 in OKC&lt;/a&gt;. A great cover
 of a great album.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Brothers-Black-Keys/dp/B003AO1SVS/ref=sr_1_1?s=music&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593281&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;The
 Black Keys - Brothers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; I listened to this album over and over this past summer. Nice
 gritty bluesy rock.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Odd-Blood-Yeasayer/dp/B0030E5NKU/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593310&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Yeasayer
 - Odd Blood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Another band I saw live this year. Upbeat indie rock to enliven any task or
 workout.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Astro-Coast-Surfer-Blood/dp/B002ZPIBG8/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593332&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Surfer
 Blood - Astro Coast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Surf rock sound thanks to lots of Telecaster but new and different
 at the same time. Plus a song about &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0000186/"&gt;David Lynch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Say-Born-Ruffians/dp/B003A2HXAK/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593352&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Born
 Ruffians - Say It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; I saw these guys play at the &lt;a
 href="http://blogs.houstonpress.com/rocks/2010/09/i_want_this_place_to.php"&gt;newly reopened
 Fitzgerald's&lt;/a&gt; in my 'hood. Great live show. Catchy album.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Transference-Spoon/dp/B002VDZIIS/ref=sr_1_1?s=music&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593396&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Spoon
 - Transference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Few bands consistently release great albums while gradually morphing
 their sound. Spoon does. Another constant listen this past year.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/King-Beach-Wavves/dp/B003SNYZVG/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593414&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Wavves
 - King of the Beach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The summer of 2010 was a brief indie surf rock renaissance. Or maybe
 I'm discounting a trend with a longer shelf life. But I'm no critic. Good album for the beach. Or kings
 of them.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a
 href="http://www.amazon.com/Wild-Smile-Suckers/dp/B003HLT0BO/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1293593441&amp;amp;sr=1-1"&gt;Suckers
 - Wild Smile&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; These guys toured with Local Natives and the first time I heard them was
 when they opened that show. Bad ass tunes kinda like Local Natives but not. Apples and oranges, but
 still fresh &amp;amp; delicious organic fruit (I may have yuppied that fruit part up a bit, but oh well).
 &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://giantprincess.blogspot.com/p/merch.html"&gt;Giant Princess - Zip Zop Wow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Awesome
 new band from the H Tizzle. Raucous indie rock. Saw them do an in store at my beloved &lt;a
 href="http://twitter.com/#!/cactus_music"&gt;Cactus Music&lt;/a&gt; and dug it.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Indie Rock Mix CD for My Canada/Montreal Trip</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/07/07/indie-rock-mix-cd-for-my-canada/montreal-trip/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2010/07/07/indie-rock-mix-cd-for-my-canada/montreal-trip/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'&gt;
 Any good trip needs a soundtrack. With this in mind, I created a mix CD with the following tracks. All of the bands
 except where noted hail from Montreal or at least Canada. I've included links to listen to the tracks on YouTube. No
 Celine Dion or Bryan Adams will be found here, only the coolest indie bands Canada has to offer.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;These are in no particular order. I know, I know... the art of a good mix is in the song order, but I plan to
 put the CD on shuffle in the rental car to let chance determine what we hear when:&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=CMSVCKsHRks"&gt;Of Montreal - An Eluardian Instance&lt;/a&gt; (Not
 FROM Montreal, but it's in their name)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=J6Ppc_4Be5o"&gt;Built to Spill - Hindsight&lt;/a&gt; (Not FROM
 Canada, but the lyric "What about Canada? It's paradise. It's pines and ice." makes me chuckle every
 time I hear it.)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EcDYMpQlFLA"&gt;Arcade Fire - Month of May&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Lb9WKJhqVWs"&gt;Broken Social Scene - World Sick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=56_MTZDXwZU"&gt;Hot Hot Heat - Middle of Nowhere&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ABhrrytjL_E"&gt;Wolf Parade - Ghost Pressure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mqIHptgTam0"&gt;Islands - Rough Gem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hpvqU2cmK8I"&gt;New Pornographers - Use It&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iRZ_SWA_SbA"&gt;Postal Service - Mushaboom&lt;/a&gt; (Remix of the
 Feist song. She's from Canada.)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MkMIxJrrz10"&gt;Tokyo Police Club - Breakneck Speed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QyDPUaW6kwA"&gt;Born Ruffians - Foxes Mate for Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AZW9NYX6JZA"&gt;St Vincent - Actor Out of Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Yq_tDOFU5tY"&gt;Caribou - Odessa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U8KAU9vWGgc"&gt;Tegan &amp;amp; Sara - Back in Your Head&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jOoHAbnhxNI"&gt;Japandroids - Young Hearts Spark Fire&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qLVIsbLy_5Q"&gt;AC Newman - Palace at 4 AM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xnnuGZ3QKgM"&gt;Sunset Rubdown - Idiot Heart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3mIZooCIQ3o"&gt;The Unicorns - Jellybones&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bands I've Seen Live</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 09:12:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2009/04/19/bands-ive-seen-live/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking for quite some time about trying to compile a list of all the bands I&amp;rsquo;ve seen live over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ll put these in order as much as possible. I plan to keep adding to this as I recall past shows and attend more in the future. I have a ticket stub book, so I&amp;rsquo;ll include the dates and other details for those I have. Some of these are special in that the bands have since split up, are no longer touring, and/or some members have passed away. You can find videos from a lot of these shows on my &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/dammitandy"&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; channel. Here we go:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My latest adventures</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/11/08/my-latest-adventures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/11/08/my-latest-adventures/</guid><description>&lt;div class='post'&gt;
 Again, too long between blog posts.  My faithful readers are clammoring for more of my adventures.  Right?  Well,
 most likely not, but here it goes...&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;First, Jamie and I went to the &lt;a href="http://www.aclfestival.com/default.aspx"&gt;ACL Festival&lt;/a&gt; in Austin
 about a month ago.  It was the first time to go for both of us and we saw a ton of great bands including &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/vampireweekend"&gt;Vampire Weekend&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/bobbybarejr"&gt;Bobby Bare Jr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/matesofstate"&gt;Mates of State&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/jennylewismusic"&gt;Jenny Lewis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/theold97s"&gt;Old 97's&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/josegonzalez"&gt;Jose
 Gonzalez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/drivebytruckers"&gt;Drive-By Truckers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/canseidesersexy"&gt;Cansei de ser Sexy (CSS)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/mgmt"&gt;MGMT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/conoroberst"&gt;Conor Oberst&lt;/a&gt;,
 and &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/beck"&gt;Beck&lt;/a&gt;.  Here's a video I took of Beck doing "Hell Yes":&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div style="text-align: center"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object width="425" height="344"&gt;
 &lt;param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/GPbJGz5RL7s&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1"&gt;
 &lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"&gt;
 &lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always"&gt;&lt;embed
 src="http://www.youtube.com/v/GPbJGz5RL7s&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash"
 allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" width="425" height="344"&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;Check out the rest of the videos I took &lt;a
 href="http://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=dammitandy+acl&amp;amp;search_type=&amp;amp;aq=f"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  I
 managed to escape without a sunburn thanks to liberal application of SPF 50 sunscreen and a hat, but the
 allergies were another story.  Apparently, Austin is unofficially the &lt;a
 href="http://www.barrypopik.com/index.php/new_york_city/entry/allergy_capital_of_the_world_austin_nickname/"&gt;allergy
 capital of the world&lt;/a&gt;.  It hit me so hard I was sneezing constantly and wishing Tylenol made a "snot
 buckets" formula.  But I had a blast.  I can't wait to find out who will be there next year.&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;Other concerts I've been to recently include &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/ryanadams"&gt;Ryan Adams &amp;amp; The
 Cardinals&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/thetingtings"&gt;The Ting Tings&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a
 href="http://www.myspace.com/weezer"&gt;Weezer&lt;/a&gt;.  The Ryan Adams show was at Verizon Wireless Theater.  It
 was my third time to see him and he's one of those artists who sounds even better live.  They played a lot of
 songs from their new album.  I saw The Ting Tings at the new Houston House of Blues.  I was not impressed with
 the place as a restaurant nor as a concert venue, but the band put on a good show.  My only criticism would be
 that the amount of effort the two band members put into constantly jumping between instruments and grabbing them
 from roadies at just the right point in the song detracted from their performance a bit.  Would it be THAT bad
 to add an extra member for touring?  The Weezer show was at Reliant Arena.  It was my second time to see them
 live.  Highlights include a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3UfzjY0fHBI"&gt;note-for-note perfect
 performance of Pink Floyd's "Time"&lt;/a&gt; and about 30 local amateur musicians playing a variety of instruments
 (guitars, flutes, saxaphones, trumpets, tubas, hand drums, etc.) with Weezer themselves just singing for a few
 songs (here's &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vFBd97rDXyA"&gt;Island in the Sun&lt;/a&gt;).  Even funnier was
 Rivers pointing to a couple people to play the solos in the songs.&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;I'm going to see &lt;a href="http://www.myspace.com/ofmontreal"&gt;Of Montreal&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday night.  They were
 amazing when I saw them the first time last year, so it should be another good show.  Their new album is a bit
 schizophrenic, but who really wants to listen to a band who becomes formulaic and fails to evolve?  Speaking of
 new music, I grabbed the &lt;a href="http://www.pitchforkmedia.com/node/147226"&gt;new Ryan Adams on vinyl&lt;/a&gt;
 (complete with a bonus 7" and alternate cover art) last night.  And I can't get &lt;a
 href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=97WPxtEtTEU"&gt;Matt &amp;amp; Kim's new song "Daylight"&lt;/a&gt; out of my head.
  It's perfect to crank up while driving around with the windows down and sunroof open this time of year.&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;The guys from &lt;a href="http://guestroom-records.com/"&gt;Guest Room Records&lt;/a&gt; in Oklahoma City/Norman have a
 podcast called "&lt;a href="http://shoesareforwork.libsyn.com/"&gt;Shoes Are for Work&lt;/a&gt;".  They play about 10 indie
 rock songs in each episode and discuss new releases.  I highly recommend it if you're a music freak like I am.
 &lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;And now, the running update.  My marathon training has been going well since I picked up some &lt;a
 href="http://www.slstri.com/catalog/item/6600182/6463940.htm"&gt;SLS Compression Sox&lt;/a&gt; (AKA dork socks) a
 little over a month ago.  My calves/feet are a lot less sore after running with them and they make longer runs
 much easier.  Props to Brett for mentioning these on his &lt;a href="http://www.zentriathlon.com/blog/"&gt;Zen &amp;amp;
 The Art of Triathlon&lt;/a&gt; podcast.  I've also taken his suggestion of doing 10 pushups for every mile on my
 shorter runs.  Running six miles and doing 60 pushups in less than an hour is manly.  I dare you to say
 otherwise.&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;I did a 20 mile run a couple weekends ago in about 3:30 and burned 3919 calories (that's more than a pound!)
 along the way:&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;a onblur="try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}"
 href="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SRXpbH5qhOI/AAAAAAAAADo/NFwKi09sfVU/s1600-h/DSCF0384.JPG"&gt;&lt;img
 style="display:block; margin:0px auto 10px; text-align:center;cursor:pointer; cursor:hand;width: 320px; height: 240px;"
 src="http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SRXpbH5qhOI/AAAAAAAAADo/NFwKi09sfVU/s320/DSCF0384.JPG"
 border="0" alt="" id="BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5266371991466312930" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;That was a semi-relaxed pace, so hopefully I can finish the &lt;a href="http://www.rnrsa.com/home.html"&gt;San
 Antonio Rock N Roll Marathon&lt;/a&gt; next weekend in 4:15-4:30.  Since this will be my first marathon, I'm
 trying not to be too concerned about the time.&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;I guess that's enough for this variety pack of the life and times of Andy.  Maybe I should post more often so
 each entry can have a topic and a meaningful title.  Hmmm...something to consider...&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>