<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kotlin on Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/categories/kotlin/</link><description>Recent content in Kotlin on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 20:05:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/categories/kotlin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Family Tree DSL with Jetpack Compose syntax</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/21/building-a-family-tree-dsl-with-jetpack-compose-syntax/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 20:05:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/21/building-a-family-tree-dsl-with-jetpack-compose-syntax/</guid><description>Originally published on ProAndroidDev
Why build a DSL? Ever since first getting into Kotlin, I&amp;rsquo;ve known it has a few things that makes building domain-specific languages (DSLs) easier. I&amp;rsquo;ve read the mind-expanding type-safe builders guide for building a DSL for HTML, but until recently I hadn&amp;rsquo;t found a good use case for building a DSL of my own.
My team at Zalando maintains server-driven UI libraries for Android &amp;amp; iOS that power completely dynamic screens such as home, brand homes, collections, and various landing pages in the Zalando fashion store apps.</description></item><item><title>Flexbox Layout Behavior in Jetpack Compose</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/16/flexbox-layout-behavior-in-jetpack-compose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 10:31:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2021/03/16/flexbox-layout-behavior-in-jetpack-compose/</guid><description>Originally published on the Zalando Engineering Blog
Introduction The CSS Flexible Box Layout specification (AKA flexbox) is a useful abstraction for describing layouts in a platform agnostic way. For this reason, it is widely used on the web and even on mobile. Readers familiar with ConstraintLayout can think of flexbox as conceptually similar to the Flow virtual layout it supports. This type of layout is ideal for grids or other groups of views with varying sizes.</description></item></channel></rss>