<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saint Arnold on Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/categories/saint-arnold/</link><description>Recent content in Saint Arnold on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/categories/saint-arnold/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mates of State Concert &amp; Restaurant Stuff</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/15/mates-of-state-concert-restaurant-stuff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/15/mates-of-state-concert-restaurant-stuff/</guid><description>Jamie I saw Mates of State this past Thursday at Warehouse Live. I've really been digging their new album, Re-Arrange Us and it was my first time to see them live. For only two people, their unique combination of keyboard, drums, and vocal harmony makes for a nice, full sound. I picked their latest up on vinyl, which overflowed my record collection into its 2nd crate.
Here's a video I took of "</description></item><item><title>French Kicks Show, New Records, and a 10 Mile Run</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/08/french-kicks-show-new-records-and-a-10-mile-run/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/08/french-kicks-show-new-records-and-a-10-mile-run/</guid><description>Once again, I packed a lot of fun into the weekend. Jamie and I went to the French Kicks concert at Walter's on Friday night with some friends. Houston's own Young Mammals (formerly The Dimes) opened and made me a fan almost instantly. It was my second time to see the French Kicks and they put on a great show yet again.
I took it easy Saturday. I got a humidor for some quality cigars I recently procured and then paid another visit to my music mecca, Cactus Records.</description></item><item><title>Camping @ Pace Bend &amp; A New Personal Record For Downhill Speed!</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/04/camping-pace-bend-a-new-personal-record-for-downhill-speed/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/04/camping-pace-bend-a-new-personal-record-for-downhill-speed/</guid><description>I had a great time camping this weekend with some friends at Pace Bend Park next to Lake Travis, TX. For the most part, we just hung out enjoying tasty beer (Saint Arnold's Lawnmower/Summer Pilsner/Amber and Sierra Nevada Pale Ale for you connoisseurs), a fine Cuban cigar, and the perfect weather. One of the highlights of the trip for me was setting a new personal record for downhill speed on our 35 mile bike ride around the lake.</description></item></channel></rss>