<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Top 10 on Andy Dyer</title>
    <link>https://andydyer.org/categories/top-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top 10 on Andy Dyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/categories/top-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m a bit late with my annual Top 10 list, but here it is roughly ranked by Google Music play count:
 Earl Sweatshirt - I Don&#39;t Like Shit, I Don&#39;t Go Outside I was finally lucky enough to see him live and he didn&#39;t disappoint. Another great release. This soundtracked numerous skateboard and chill sessions. Vince Staples - Summertime &amp;lsquo;06 His &amp;ldquo;Hell Can Wait&amp;rdquo; EP made my list last year and I knew this one would be on this year&#39;s list right away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums of 2014</title>
      <link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>The end of another year means it&#39;s time for the annual Top 10 Favorite Albums list.
 Ty Segall - Manipulator While not the leader in sheer track plays via my Google Play Music account, this album is perfect all the way through. It certainly spent a lot of time on my turntable as well. Nothing - Guilty of Everything A wonderful example of the specific brand of rock music I love.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums of 2013</title>
      <link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</guid>
      <description>Each year, I keep a list of albums that I find myself listening to frequently. This is the time of year when I review the list and pick my top 10. I ventured into hip-hop and electronic music a bit more this year. Psych rock and 90s style fuzz are also well represented.
 My Bloody Valentine - MBV Disclosure - Settle Swearin&amp;rsquo; - Dust in the Gold Sack Weed - Deserve Thee Oh Sees - Floating Coffin Night Beats - Sonic Bloom Speedy Ortiz - Major Arcana Unknown Mortal Orchestra - II Waxahatchee - Cerulean Salt Earl Sweatshirt - Doris  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>