<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Andy Dyer</title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Andy Dyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 12:45:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I&#39;ve Learned Since Moving to Berlin</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 12:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2017/09/23/things-ive-learned-since-moving-to-berlin/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;ve lived in Berlin for a bit more than six months now. Here&#39;s a list of some of the things I&#39;ve learned:
 It is possible to survive a summer without air conditioning. It&#39;s also possible to go all summer without a mosquito bite. I don&#39;t miss having a car. Public transit is great here so I typically only need one to haul things like furniture. And I can rent one on demand pretty easily with apps like DriveNow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aufwiedersehen, Houston! Hallo, Berlin!</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 13:06:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2017/02/02/aufwiedersehen-houston-hallo-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who has talked to me for more than 10 minutes has probably heard me mention my love for Berlin. I first visited the city about six years ago and almost immediately resolved to make it my home one day. I&#39;m thrilled to finally announce that it&#39;s happening! I&#39;ll be joining Zalando in Berlin next month to do Android and hopefully step up my fashion game a bit. Radical Agility sounds like engineering nirvana to me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surprised this domain was available</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2013/07/14/surprised-this-domain-was-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2013/07/14/surprised-this-domain-was-available/</guid>
      <description>I finally got around to registering a domain name and setting up a basic Octopress site. I&#39;ll be posting here about music/code/coffee/beer/life releated stuff when the mood strikes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>