<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Apps on Andy Dyer</title><link>https://andydyer.org/categories/apps/</link><description>Recent content in Apps on Andy Dyer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 20:53:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://andydyer.org/categories/apps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Biografy</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/12/24/introducing-biografy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 20:53:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2017/12/24/introducing-biografy/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="what-is-biografy"&gt;What is Biografy?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.biografy"&gt;Biografy&lt;/a&gt; is a lifelogging app that automatically builds a timeline of each day. The &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/events.png"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Events&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; view logs events from various apps including music, podcasts, videos, calls and chats. Each event includes rich detail such as the time, activity (stationary, walking, biking, etc.), and location/place. The &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/motion.png"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Motion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; view lists car/transit trips, bike rides, runs, and walks. With the &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/map.png"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Map&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; view, you can see where you were when each event occurred and gain insights like where you spend your time based on the clusters of pins. Finally, the &lt;a href="https://andydyer.org/images/biografy/notes.png"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; view is perfect for adding context to remember each day. Want to travel back in time? Simply tap the toolbar to choose the date.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using a Third Party FAB with CoordinatorLayout</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/28/using-a-third-party-fab-with-coordinatorlayout/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/06/28/using-a-third-party-fab-with-coordinatorlayout/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Before the Design Support Library was announced at Google I/O last month, I had numerous third party libraries in my projects for various elements of Material Design. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed replacing the nav drawer, tabs, and parallax scrolling libraries with their support library counterparts. However, on one of my projects, we needed an expanding floating action button (FAB) similar to the one in &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.google.android.apps.inbox"&gt;Inbox&lt;/a&gt;, which the support library does not currently provide.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Loading a List of Objects from Firebase</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/04/06/loading-a-list-of-objects-from-firebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/04/06/loading-a-list-of-objects-from-firebase/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with &lt;a href="https://www.firebase.com/"&gt;Firebase&lt;/a&gt; lately in preparation for adding data synchronization to my &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary"&gt;Music Library&lt;/a&gt; app. Their &lt;a href="https://www.firebase.com/docs/android/quickstart.html"&gt;docs&lt;/a&gt; did a great job of getting me set up. Using the &lt;a href="https://github.com/firebase/firebase-login-demo-android"&gt;sample app&lt;/a&gt; as a guide, I even got Google+ OAuth working without much trouble. From there, it didn&amp;rsquo;t take long to load data into a Firebase instance partitioned by Google account. All that was left was to query the data out of Firebase and I&amp;rsquo;d be able to see the sync magic in action.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I'm Unironically Carrying This Small, Older Android Phone</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed my last night in Berlin a little over a week ago; so much that I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice my phone was missing until the end of the night. Shake your head and say it couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen to you. I thought the same thing until it did. Normally, I keep my phone in one of my front pockets, but I was wearing a coat that covered the pocket, making it a bit more difficult to grab my phone quickly to check Google Maps. Since my coat has a side access pocket in the chest, I stowed my phone there while walking around. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing a skillful thief at the last bar spotted my phone in that side pocket and was able to slide it out without me knowing. I was in a crowded room and often looking to one side as I talked to different people. Self-shaming thoughts aside, sometimes it happens.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Music Library 3.0 - Material Design Update</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/11/02/music-library-3.0-material-design-update/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/11/02/music-library-3.0-material-design-update/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/music_library_icon.png" alt="Music Library" style="width: 150px; float: left; margin-right: 20px" /&gt;
I started developing [Music Library](https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary) about four years ago when I wanted an app for organizing my record collection. Armed with my Nexus One, Eclipse, and a copy of Apress' [Pro Android](http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1430246804/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;camp=1789&amp;creative=9325&amp;creativeASIN=1430246804&amp;linkCode=as2&amp;tag=slacod-20&amp;linkId=FMLK73AOGDPPJEM3), I spent my nights and weekends learning the inner workings of my now-favorite mobile OS.
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Music Library has been a playground of sorts for exploring various open source libraries, patterns, and best practices. While there is still a fair amount of code I would write differently today (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you, ContentProvider), the app has been and continues to be an enjoyable side project.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Android's Material Design and The Bauhaus</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/13/androids-material-design-and-the-bauhaus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/13/androids-material-design-and-the-bauhaus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Since Android Gingerbread (v2.3), loyalists know that each version has an Easter egg that can be accessed by repeatedly tapping the version number on the Settings &amp;gt; About screen. The Android &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo; Preview is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While test driving the new version, I naturally had to see what Google had hidden for me in their latest release. Previous versions have had everything from &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PeAFCIvqNxc"&gt;gingerbread zombies&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DfY73GBBHxg"&gt;Nyandroids&lt;/a&gt; and a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iN-nJdAJS7g"&gt;pile of jelly beans&lt;/a&gt;. The Android &amp;ldquo;L&amp;rdquo; Preview build has a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_He5MIYJas8"&gt;simple animation of random overlapping red and blue rectangles&lt;/a&gt;. Several Android blogs mentioned this, but dismissed it as &lt;a href="http://www.androidcentral.com/android-l-Previews-easter-egg-webdriver-torso"&gt;mysterious&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.slashgear.com/hands-on-with-the-android-l-features-google-didnt-mention-27335613/"&gt;strange&lt;/a&gt;. While these random rectangles are clearly the same used by Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/technology-27778071"&gt;WebDriver Torso&lt;/a&gt; YouTube video quality testing, so far everyone seems to have missed the most obvious explanation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fun with Android Wear</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/12/fun-with-android-wear/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/07/12/fun-with-android-wear/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/deutschuhr_androidwear.png" alt="Deutsch Uhr" style="width: 140px; float: left; margin-right: 20px" /&gt;I got my &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/devices/details?id=lg_g_watch_black"&gt;LG G Android Wear&lt;/a&gt; smart watch earlier this week and dove right into developing for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first project was &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.deutschuhr"&gt;Deutsch Uhr&lt;/a&gt;, a text-based German language watch face inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/url?q=http://www.mypebblefaces.com/apps/1446/1484/&amp;amp;sa=D&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHn1MUA0IUtwhRwqFGHYKorEIcmLg"&gt;my favorite Pebble watch face&lt;/a&gt;. I had fun adding animations for the hour/minute/day changes and learning what makes a Wear app tick (pun intended, I always do). A big thanks to my friend Daniel Ward for help getting started. Be sure to check out his &lt;a href="http://phandroid.com/2014/07/06/custom-android-wear-watch-faces-binary-clock/"&gt;Binary Watch Face&lt;/a&gt;, which was the first Android Wear watch face to appear on Google Play a couple weeks ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Presenting: Wrist Presenter for Android and the Pebble Smartwatch</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/03/07/presenting-wrist-presenter-for-android-and-the-pebble-smartwatch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2014/03/07/presenting-wrist-presenter-for-android-and-the-pebble-smartwatch/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://andydyer.org/images/wristpresenter_icon@2x.png" alt="Wrist Presenter" style="width: 150px; float: left; margin-right: 20px" /&gt;
Shortly after getting a Pebble Smartwatch this past Christmas, my coworker and all-around-cool-dude [Matthew Morey](http://matthewmorey.com/) asked me if I'd be interested in developing the Android version of his [Wrist Presenter iOS app](http://matthewmorey.com/wrist-presenter/). Luckily, he already had a rock solid Pebble app developed, so I didn't have to flex my meager C programming skills.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wristpresenter.com/"&gt;Wrist Presenter&lt;/a&gt; turns your Pebble Smartwatch into a remote for presentations running on your Android or iOS device.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introducing Kollektor</title><link>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/28/introducing-kollektor/</guid><description>&lt;h5 id="why-a-new-app"&gt;Why a new app?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first decided to get into Android development, I created the &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.dandydev.medialibrary"&gt;Music Library&lt;/a&gt; app to catalog my vinyl collection. It served me well as I learned the ins and outs of Android programming including &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/providers/content-providers.html"&gt;content providers&lt;/a&gt;, interacting with other applications via &lt;a href="http://developer.android.com/reference/android/content/Intent.html"&gt;intents&lt;/a&gt;, working with the file system to save/load images, making API requests, etc. In order to test the workings of the Android app market, I published the ad supported Music Library Free and the paid Music Library versions of the app. In addition to not displaying ads, Music Library also included the ability to backup your collection to the device&amp;rsquo;s SD card and export data to a Google Drive spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>